<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" generated="2014-12-25T17:05:03">
<vqplan>
<ID>1</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Able To</Title>
<Details>To be able to </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>2</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Included</Title>
<Details>The objectives for this StudyTopic lesson have been included within each lesson section.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>3</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Address</Title>
<Details>To be able to address the problems you identify with your StudyTopic work.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>4</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Analyze</Title>
<Details>To be able to critically analyze and evaluate information about StudyTopic, identifying the pros and the cons. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>5</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Annotate</Title>
<Details>To be able to annotate the StudyTopic text. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>6</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Answer</Title>
<Details>To be able to answer the StudyTopic question(s). </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>7</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Apply Knowledge</Title>
<Details>To be able to apply knowledge of StudyTopic in order to solve 3 problems. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>245</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Starter</Title>
<Details>Groups of 2. You have 10 minutes to complete this task. Your StudyTopic task is to </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>246</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Not Appropriate</Title>
<Details>A starter activity is not appropriate to the structure of this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>247</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Act Out: Character</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer StudyTopic questions in the voice of different characters. This is a lively and theatrical way to start our StudyTopic lesson. Look at the questions on the board: What is StudyTopic? Where do we find StudyTopic? When did you last see StudyTopic? What words are connected to StudyTopic? Why is StudyTopic important? Groups of 2. Take one character card. [Cards: A Businessperson, A Teacher, A Student, A King, A Queen, President Obama, Angry, Impatient, Happy]. In your groups choose a question and then take turns to answer it in the style of the character that is written on your card. Guess the style that the question has been answered in [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>248</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Answer: 8 Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer 8 questions about different aspects of StudyTopic. We are going to stimulate our thinking about StudyTopic by considering 8 questions. Draw an octagon with &apos;StudyTopic&apos; in the middle [1 min]. On each face write the answer to one of these questions: How many different types of StudyTopic are there? Where does the word StudyTopic come from? Which people have been involved in creating and using StudyTopic? What emotions are involved with StudyTopic? How does StudyTopic affect the environment? What do people do with StudyTopic? What songs or sounds are about StudyTopic? What images represent StudyTopic? [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>249</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Answer: Pass The Parcel</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer questions about StudyTopic. We will have a thought provoking pass the parcel start to this lesson. In this parcel there is an object that is connected to StudyTopic. If you are able to answer a question about StudyTopic then you are allowed to unwrap one layer. First I will ask a question and then we will pick a student to try to answer the question [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>250</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Answer: True Or False</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer True or False questions about StudyTopic. This is an excellent, quick-fire true or false activity. I am going to read 3 questions and 3 statements about StudyTopic. For each one you need to decide if it is true or false. After I read each one I will be asking you to give the reason(s) for your choice [6 mins]. It is now your turn to make your own StudyTopic True Or False statements. You must have at least 2 false and 2 true statements. Think about the reasons that they are true or false [6 mins]. Share your statements with your partner and explain them [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>251</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Argue: For A Proposition</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to argue for and against StudyTopic. This is a vocalized and assertive way to start our StudyTopic lesson. Class split into 4 groups. Today we are going to practice arguing - regardless of our own personal opinion. Group 1, you are going to defend proposition A. Group 2, you are going to refute proposition A. Group 3, you are going to defend proposition B. Group 4, you are going to refute proposition B. Proposition A: &apos;StudyTopic is the most important thing in the whole world&apos;. Proposition B: &apos;StudyTopic will be the cause of the next world war&apos; [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>8</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Apply Techniques</Title>
<Details>To be able to apply techniques about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>9</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Appraise</Title>
<Details>To be able to appraise 2 arguments for and 2 arguments against StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>10</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Appreciate</Title>
<Details>To be able to appreciate the importance of StudyTopic in terms of academia and to society as a whole. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>11</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Argue</Title>
<Details>To be able to argue for and against StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>12</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Arrange</Title>
<Details>To be able to arrange information about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>13</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Articulate</Title>
<Details>To be able to articulate the differences between StudyTopic and similar concepts. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>14</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Ask</Title>
<Details>To be able to ask questions about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>15</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Assemble</Title>
<Details>To be able to assemble the parts of StudyTopic into an effective whole. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>16</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Assess</Title>
<Details>To be able to assess the importance of different parts of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>17</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Attribute</Title>
<Details>To be able to attribute the causes and effects of StudyTopic in different situations. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>18</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Calculate</Title>
<Details>To be able to carry out calculations about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>19</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Calculate Answers</Title>
<Details>To be able to calculate the answers to StudyTopic problems.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>20</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Categorize</Title>
<Details>To be able to categorize information about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>21</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Classify</Title>
<Details>To be able to classify different forms of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>22</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Collect</Title>
<Details>To be able to collect information about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>23</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Combine</Title>
<Details>To be able to combine information about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>24</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Communicate</Title>
<Details>To be able to communicate information about StudyTopic through presentation and discussion. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>25</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Compare</Title>
<Details>To be able to compare and contrast thoughts about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>26</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Compose Poem</Title>
<Details>To be able to compose a poem about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>27</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Compose Song</Title>
<Details>To be able to compose a song about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>28</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Construct</Title>
<Details>To be able to construct an argument in favor and against StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>29</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Continue</Title>
<Details>To continue with the work started during the last lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>30</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Contrast</Title>
<Details>To be able to contrast different interpretations of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>31</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Create</Title>
<Details>To be able to create StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>32</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Criticize</Title>
<Details>To be able to criticize an argument for StudyTopic and criticize an argument against StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>33</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Debate</Title>
<Details>To be able to take part in a debate about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>34</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Decision</Title>
<Details>To be able to make a decision about StudyTopic from the perspectives of: An Individual, A Family, Society, The Environment. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>35</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Deconstruct</Title>
<Details>To be able to deconstruct the parts of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>36</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Define</Title>
<Details>To be able to define StudyTopic and StudyTopic terms. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>37</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Demonstrate</Title>
<Details>To be able to carry out a demonstration of how StudyTopic works.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>38</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Describe</Title>
<Details>To be able to name the parts of StudyTopic and to describe what they look like. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>39</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Design</Title>
<Details>To be able to produce a detailed StudyTopic design. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>40</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Develop</Title>
<Details>To be able to develop an improved StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>41</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Devise</Title>
<Details>To be able to devise a new kind of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>42</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Diagnose</Title>
<Details>To be able to diagnose the StudyTopic problem and identify a solution. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>43</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Dictation</Title>
<Details>To be able to accurately take down a dictation about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>44</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Discover</Title>
<Details>To be able to discover aspects of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>45</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Discuss</Title>
<Details>To be able to discuss StudyTopic, thinking about both the positive and negative aspects. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>46</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Display</Title>
<Details>To be able to display data about StudyTopic using an appropriate and correct drawn graph.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>47</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Distinguish</Title>
<Details>To be able to distinguish between the different varieties of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>48</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Distribute</Title>
<Details>To be able to distribute information about StudyTopic using the internet or leaflets.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>49</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Dramatize</Title>
<Details>To be able to dramatize StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>50</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Edit</Title>
<Details>To be able to edit your StudyTopic work, correcting the mistakes you identify.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>51</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Evaluate</Title>
<Details>To be able to evaluate the importance of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>52</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Examine</Title>
<Details>To be able to examine the parts of StudyTopic and to explain how those parts come together to form a whole. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>53</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Experiment</Title>
<Details>To be able to carry out an experiment to prove how StudyTopic works. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>54</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Explain How</Title>
<Details>To be able to name the parts /types of StudyTopic and explain how they work.  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>55</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Explain What</Title>
<Details>To be able to explain what StudyTopic is and how it is produced. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>56</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Explore</Title>
<Details>To explore contemporary and historical developments in StudyTopic and to analyze how the developments have been communicated. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>57</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Find</Title>
<Details>To be able to find relevant information about StudyTopic and use that as a basis for further work. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>58</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Graph</Title>
<Details>To be able to draw graphs about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>59</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Hypothesize</Title>
<Details>To be able to make a hypothesis about how StudyTopic works. Then to test that hypothesis and explain why it is or is not correct. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>60</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Identify Improvements</Title>
<Details>To be able to identify improvements that can be made to StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>61</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Identify Qualities</Title>
<Details>To be able to identify the qualities of StudyTopic and explain why each of them are important.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>62</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Illustrate</Title>
<Details>To be able to illustrate StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>63</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Improve</Title>
<Details>To be able to improve your work about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>64</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Interpret</Title>
<Details>To be able to interpret data about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>65</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Interview</Title>
<Details>To be able to ask and answer interview questions about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>66</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Invent</Title>
<Details>To be able to invent a product that uses StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>67</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Investigate</Title>
<Details>To be able to investigate StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>68</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Judge</Title>
<Details>To be able to judge StudyTopic from the perspective of: A Police Officer, A Politician, A Citizen. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>69</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Label</Title>
<Details>To be able to label a diagram about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>70</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>List</Title>
<Details>To be able to list words connected to StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>71</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Listen</Title>
<Details>To be able to listen and take notes about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>72</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Make</Title>
<Details>To be able to make StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>73</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Make Links</Title>
<Details>To be able to make links between StudyTopic and other subjects. To be able to explain the influence that StudyTopic has on those subjects. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>74</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Make Notes</Title>
<Details>To be able to make notes about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>75</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Marvel</Title>
<Details>To be able to marvel at the wonder of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>76</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Memorize</Title>
<Details>To be able to memorize information about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>77</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Model</Title>
<Details>To be able to build a model which accurately illustrates the ideas and concepts of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>78</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Observe</Title>
<Details>To be able to make observations of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>79</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Organize</Title>
<Details>To be able to organize the different parts of StudyTopic into a functioning whole. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>80</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Outline</Title>
<Details>To be able to outline the parts of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>81</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Perform</Title>
<Details>To be able to carry out a performance about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>82</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Personalize</Title>
<Details>To be able to personalize the StudyTopic learning objectives (make them as specific as you can) and deliver on my personalized objective. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>83</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Plan</Title>
<Details>To be able to draw/create a plan of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>84</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Play</Title>
<Details>To be able to play with the ideas of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>85</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Predict</Title>
<Details>To be able to predict the outcome of StudyTopic is range of situations.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>86</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Question</Title>
<Details>To be able to formulate questions about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>87</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Read</Title>
<Details>To be able to read a piece about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>88</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Recap</Title>
<Details>To be able to recap and then build on previous learning about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>89</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Recite</Title>
<Details>To be able to recite a passage or poem about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>90</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Recognize</Title>
<Details>To be able to recognize the components of StudyTopic and a range of StudyTopic examples.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>91</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Reconstruct</Title>
<Details>To be able to reconstruct the parts of StudyTopic into an effective whole.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>92</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Record</Title>
<Details>To be able to record observations about StudyTopic and then comment on them. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>93</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Record Video</Title>
<Details>To be able to record and edit a video about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>94</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Redraw</Title>
<Details>To be able to redraw a picture about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>95</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Reflect</Title>
<Details>To be able to reflect on your learning about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>96</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Relate</Title>
<Details>To be able to relate my understanding of StudyTopic to a real life example. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>97</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Reorganize</Title>
<Details>To be able to reorganize StudyTopic into a complete whole.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>98</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Report</Title>
<Details>To be able to produce a report about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>99</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Reproduce</Title>
<Details>To be able to reppoduce StudyTopic information skills and techniques. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>100</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Research</Title>
<Details>To be able to research StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>101</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Respond</Title>
<Details>To be able to respond to criticism about your StudyTopic work.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>102</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Restructure</Title>
<Details>To be able to restructure information about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>103</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Retell</Title>
<Details>To be able to retell the StudyTopic story.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>104</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Revise</Title>
<Details>To be able to revise work about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>105</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Rewrite</Title>
<Details>To be able to rewrite a piece about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>106</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Select</Title>
<Details>To be able to select the appropriate StudyTopic information to use. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>107</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Set Up</Title>
<Details>To be able to correctly set up StudyTopic equipment. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>108</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Simulate</Title>
<Details>To be able to create a computer simulatimn of StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>109</ID>
<Section>Objectite</Section>
<Title>Sing</Title>
<Details>To be able to sing about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>110</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Solve</Title>
<Details>To be able to solve StudyTopic problems.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>111</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Sort</Title>
<Details>To be able to sort information about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>112</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>State</Title>
<Details>To be able to state 3 facts about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>113</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Structure</Title>
<Details>To be able to structure an argument about StudyTopic and use secondary data to support your case. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>114</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Summarize</Title>
<Details>To be able to summarize the main points of StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>115</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Survey</Title>
<Details>To be able to carry out a survey of peoples’ opinions about StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>116</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Test</Title>
<Details>To be able to test the factors that influence StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>117</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Think Critically</Title>
<Details>To be able to think critically about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>118</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Translate</Title>
<Details>To be able to translate the StudyTopic passage into plain English. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>119</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Type</Title>
<Details>To be able to type information abmut StudyTopic using appropriate software and correct formatting.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>120</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Use (Equipment)</Title>
<Details>To be able to use StudyTopic equipment safely and effectively. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>121</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Use (StudyTopic)</Title>
<Details>To be able to use StudyTopic principles to identity the most effective approach to solve StudyTopic problems.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>122</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Use (Vocabulary)</Title>
<Details>To be able to use StudyTopic vocabulary and terminology in discussion and written work about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>123</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Watch And Listen</Title>
<Details>To be able to watch and listen to information about StudyTopic taking notes about 3 of the key aspects. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>124</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Write</Title>
<Details>To be able to write an essay/report/article about StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>125</ID>
<Section>Objective</Section>
<Title>Write An Objective</Title>
<Details>To be able to write my own leveled lesson objective. C) I must be able to … B) I should be able to … A) I could be able to ...</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>252</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Assess: Ability</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to assess my knowledge and ability in StudyTopic. This activity will raise your understanding of your ability. Where do you think you are: 1. I don’t know anything about StudyTopic. 2. I know one thing about StudyTopic. 3. I know a few things about StudyTopic. 4. I can use the things I know about StudyTopic make simple explanations. 5. I can use what I know about StudyTopic to make detailed explanations. [2 mins]. Your task is to come up with a learning objective for the lesson which might help you to improve [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>253</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Brainstorm: What You Know?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to brainstorm what you know about StudyTopic. In doing this brainstorm you will get a brilliant visual picture of the different aspects of StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Write out everything that you know about StudyTopic using a Brainstorm. [5 mins] Next connect the words that you think are dependent on each other. [5 mils] Now join together with the pair that are behind you and share your thoughts. After looking at their work is there anything that you would change about what you have done? [3 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>254</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Celebrate: Work Done</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to celebrate the work done. There has been so much good work that has been done and it&apos;s superb that we are going to take a few moments of think about our achievements. We are going to celebrate the work that we have done up to this point (for this term). As learners it is very important that we work effectively together. We are going to vote for &apos;The Most Helpful Student&apos; [Students Vote, 2 students count up the votes]. We are now going to have certificates for: &apos;Hardest Worker&apos;, &apos;Most Positive Influencer&apos; and &apos;Biggest Improver&apos; [Talk through and show exemplary pieces of work. Show learners just how much progress we have made. Set aspirational targets [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>255</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Choose Focus: Post It</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to choose which StudyTopic question you would like to focus on during today&apos;s lesson. This is an important task because it will give the class the focus for the rest of the lesson. Around the room are a number of StudyTopic questions. You have 5 minutes to look at the questions and discuss them [5 mins]. You each have one sticky note to vote for the StudyTopic question you would most like to focus on during the lesson. This is done by sticking your post-it note by the question. The question with the most post-its will become the focus of the lesson [1 min]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>256</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Choose: Learning Objective</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to choose the appropriate differentiated learning objective for this StudyTopic lesson. This is an important task because it will give you your own personalized learning objective for the rest of this lesson. This arrow (with StudyTopic written on it) has 3 learning objectives written along the bottom. Choose fmr yourself which of the 3 learning objectives you are going to accomplish in today’s lesson: Explain StudyTopic (C). Explore StudyTopic (B). Analyze and Evaluate StudyTopic (A). [2 mins]. For the learning objective that you have chosen expand the sentence to make it more specific and detailed [2 mins]. How far along the arrow do you think you will get?! During the lesson we will stop at various points to see how far along the arrow you are. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>257</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Classify: Impoptance</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to classify the importance of StudyTopic words. Groups of 2. This task is about your opinion and not about a &apos;right&apos; or &apos;wrong&apos; answer, you need to get on and write down what you think. Look through the liqt of 10 StudyTopic words on the board. Your task is to classify these according to their importance. Put the most important at the top and the least important at the bottom. For each word write a sentence justifying why you think it is more important than the word below it [6 mins]. Now we will discuss where you have put your words and why you have put them in the position they are in. Class discussion: What reason can you give for putting it there? Can you think of any other reasons? [4 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>258</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Complete: Flow Chart</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to complete a flow chart about StudyTopic. This task will give you a straightforward view of the flow of StudyTopic. On the interactive whiteboard is a flow chart of today&apos;s lesson (with several sections left blank). Your task is to copy out the flow chart and fill in as many of the gaps as you can [4 mins]. Display and explain the completed flow chart to compare [2 mins]. Are you able to create your own flow chart made from only images? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>259</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Conjecture: The Lesson</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to conjecture what will be covered in the lesson. For the start of this lesson you are going to exercise your powers of prediction. Groups of 2. Look at the pictorial representation of the (StudyTopic) lesson on the board. With your partner write your own conjecture of what you think this lesson will be about [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>060</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Connect: To Subjects</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to connect StudyTopic to other subjects. Write down your answer to: What were the last 3 topics we have studied [2 mins]? How, why have you chosen those [2 mins]? How is/are StudyTopic similar to, different from and related to each of the previous 3 topics [5 mins]? Share you answers with your neighbor [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>261</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Connect: Words</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to connect StudyTopic words. In this exercise we are going to activate our associative powers. Class in 2 teams. Choose a player from one team. Can you give me a word related to StudyTopic? (If the word was &apos;football&apos; the next word could be &apos;goal&apos;. The next student could then say &apos;net&apos;). Players take turns. You are allowed thinking time. At any point you can be challenged to explain the connection between your word and the previous word. I will note the number of connections on the board. [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>262</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Debate: Tolerating</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to debate the problems of StudyTopic. We are going to have a debate and it&apos;s a great opportunity for you to practice giving a succinct opinion. There are 2 rules 1. You must have something to say. 2. You must speak for no more than 10 secmnds. The first question is: Why do we have StudyTopic?[2 mins] How much StudyTopic can the world tolerate? [2 mins] What would happen if there was a law against all StudyTopic? [2 mins] Is it possible to control StudyTopic? [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>263</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Define Words: Bingo</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to correctly define StudyTopic words. This is a really fun way for us to check how well we know our StudyTopic definitions. Garden &apos;Gate, Sexy Kate, One fat lady!&apos; What am I talking about? They are all bingo words for the number 8. To start today&apos;s lesson I want you to draw a 3x3 square bingo grid [2 vertical and 2 horizontal lines creates 9 squares]. Into each square choose one of the 15 StudyTopic words that are on the board [model for learners. 2 mins]. I am going to read out a definition of one of the words. If you recognize that it is the definition of a word you have written down, then cross it off. If you cross off 3 in a line shout &apos;3 in line&apos;. If you cross off all of the gpid stand up and say &apos;BINGO!&apos; [10 mins]. For each of the 15 StudyTopic words write your own definition. Groups of 4. Each person in the group is now going to host 1 round of bingo using your word definitions. [15 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>264</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Define: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to define StudyTopic. This is going to prod you to think deeply about StudyTopic definitions. Groups of 2, spend 1 minute discussing each of these questions: How do you define StudyTopic? What does StudyTopic include? What doesn&apos;t StudyTopic include? Can you explain StudyTopic in another way? What illustration can ymu draw of StudyTopic? What specific StudyTopic examples can you think of? How many different examples of StudyTopic can you think of? Thinking of the different examples what are the different categories?  [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>265</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Definition: Find</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to find the definition of StudyTopic words. We are going to liven up StudyTopic definitions. Around the room are the definitions of 10 StudyTopic keywords (printed in large font). Your task is to move around the room and copy down a definition of all 10 StudyTopic keywords [8 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>266</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: And Draw</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe and draw StudyTopic. This task is going to challenge your drawing and your descriptive skills. Groups of 2 (AB). Sit yourselves back to back [1 min]. A’s get yourself a pad of paper and a pencil. B’s come and collect yourself a handout (a StudyTopic drawing, picture, map, flow-chart or diagram). B’s you have 2 minutes to describe the drawing to your partner, who is going to try their best to re-create the drawing from your description [2 mins]. Let’s look at the key features of the handout which I have projected onto the board for everyone to see [2 mins]. We are going to repeat and this time we are going to swap roles. B’s get your paper and pencils ready. A’s bring up the old handout when you come to collect your new StudyTopic handout [2 mins]. Let’s look at the key features of the second handout which I have projected onto the board for everyone to see [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>267</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: Image Reveal</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe the StudyTopic image. This is going to puzzle you. Look at this picture [StudyTopic picture zoomed in 2000%]. What do you think this is? [Take guesses and zoom out] What do you think this is now? [Take guesses and zoom out again] What do you think this is now? [repeat until fully revealed] What do you think is happening? What things can we see that are related to StudyTopic? What does this picture tell us about StudyTopic? [Introduce each question separately and have a group discuss. 5 mins] Your task is to write a paragraph that summarizes your thoughts about StudyTopic [5 mins]. Learners share their paragraph with their neighbor [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>268</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: Pictionary</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to communicate StudyTopic ideas through drawing. This will invigorate your ability to communicate about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Label yourselves ‘A’ and ‘B’. A&apos;s: I am going to give you a StudyTopic word, your task is to draw that word as well as you can. B&apos;s your task is to describe the things that you partner has drawn and guess what they mean. Rules: No writing words or letters. No speaking (except for A&apos;s). When you are done come and get a new word. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>269</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: Picture Before</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe what might have happened in the StudyTopic picture. You are going to need to fill up your imaginations for this task. Groups of 2. Look at this picture. Your task is to come up with your own answers to the following questions: What might have happened before the StudyTopic photo was taken? What might be happening now? What may happen after? What StudyTopic things can we seen in the photo? How does StudyTopic influence and effect what we can see? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>270</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: Pictures</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe a StudyTopic picture which qomeone else then accurately draws. Efficient teamwork is going to be really important for this task. Groups of 2 (AB). All of the A students come to the front of the classroom and take a look at this (StudyTopic) picture. The A students go back to their partner and describe what you saw. B&apos;s, your task is to draw what is described to you [1 min]. A&apos;s come back up and have 10 more seconds to look at the picture before describing again [1 min]. Show picture. B&apos;s come and have a look at this (second StudyTopic) picture. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>271</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: What&apos;s Being Said?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe what might be being said in the StudyTopic picture. This will stretch your imagination. Look at these 2 StudyTopia pictures. Choose one  picture and write a paragraph for what you think might be being said or thought? [5 mins]. Extension: Write a paragraph for the second picture.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>272</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Describe: With Adjectives </Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe StudyTopic using a variety of adjectives. You are going to need to use a lot of creativity for this task. Groups of 4. Ymu are going to say the sentence &apos;The student studies Your Adjective StudyTopic.&apos; Each time you say the sentence you are going to use a different adjective starts with the next letteps of the alphabet. The second student repeats just the last sentence said, and then says their sentence. You take it in turns to work through all of the letters from A to Z. If you can&apos;t do a letter, just move to the next one. You might start like this &apos;The student studies Advanced StudyTopic. The student studies Beautiful StudyTopic.&apos; &apos;The student studies Beautiful StudyTopic. The student studies colorful StudyTopic.&apos; [10 mins]</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>273</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Detail: Instructions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to detail the instructions for how to make StudyTopic. For this you are going to need to think deeply and methodically. What are the steps to make a cup of tea? [Take ideas] Empty the kettle, Fill the kettle, Plug in the kettle, Switch it on, Get the cup out of the cupboard, Warm the cup, Get milk out of the refrigerator, Pour the water out of the cup, Take the lid off the milk, etc. Today we are studying StudyTopic, your task is to write detailed instructions explaining how to make StudyTopic. You have 10 minutes [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>274</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discover: 20 Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discover the word connected to StudyTopic. You are going to need to think of lots of different questions once we get started with this task. First though think about StudyTopic and write down 1 connected word, it could be a person, place or idea. [Randomly select a student by throwing a soft teddy bear, the nearest student to where it lands or the catcher stands up.] As a class we have 20 yes /no questions to discover who or what has been written down [5 mins]. Repeat x2 [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>275</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Nature Of</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer questions about the nature of StudyTopic. These questions will give use an insightful and empathetic understanding of StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Discuss: What are 5 ways to make StudyTopic sad? [3 mins]  What are 3 ways to confuse StudyTopic? [3 mins] What are 5 differences between StudyTopic and a pen? [3 mins] What are 5 things that StudyTopic and a computer have in common? [3 mins] What does StudyTopic smell like? [3 mins] What feelings does StudyTopic have? [3 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>276</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Ridiculous Arguments</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss an argument about StudyTopic. In this task you are going to justify and propound your opinions. Groups of 4. We are going to be learning about StudyTopic and we will practice justifying and arguing against different scenarios. The first scenario is: &apos;Five year olds should be allowed engage in StudyTopic&apos; [students discuss and feedback] &apos;StudyTopic is something that could not exist on another planet.&apos; [students discuss and deedback] &apos;StudyTopic will `e insignificant to humanity in 50 years time.&apos; [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>277</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss StudyTopic. I am looking for everyone to make a least one contribution during the start of today&apos;s lesson. On the board is written the subject of today’s lesson: ‘StudyTopic’. I am going to randomly pick some students to share their thoughts on these questions: Have you ever heard of &apos;StudyTopic&apos;? What do you think StudyTopic is? [5 mins]. Class discussion of different aspects of StudyTopic: What do you think? Can you expand? Why is StudyTopic like that? Why do think that? Where else do we find StudyTopic? When was the first time that you heard about StudyTopic? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>278</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: StudyTopic Work</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss the StudyTopic success criteria for the lesson. We are eoing to have a think about what it really means to do well. Groups of 2. Discuss and fill in the missing word: To be able to use success criteria to _ _ _ _ _ _ _ your StudyTopic work. (Improve) [2 mins]. What are the success criteria for studying StudyTopic? [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>279</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Time/Place Lapse</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss the role that StudyTopic plays in our lives. I will want you to bring your personal experiences to this activity but first, listen. Close you eyes [check]. Listen to this short narrative. You are going to be transported to a different time and place (continue with StudyTopic narrative) [5 mins]. Discuss: What role does StudyTopic play in our lives? How do we think about StudyTopic? What do narratives and stories tell us about StudyTopic? [10 mins]</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>280</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: What If?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss &apos;What if&apos; questions about StudyTopic. Have you ever contemplated the question; what if? Groups of 2. Share your thoughts on the following ideas: What if no one was responsible for StudyTopic? What if there were no laws about StudyTopic? What if everyone stopped caring about StudyTopic? What if all StudyTopic disappear tomorrow? What if StudyTopic only happened at night? What if StudyTopic was invisible during the day? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>281</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: What Would Win?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss what would win, StudyTopic or something else. I want you to think about the language and the arguments that you are using during this discussion. I am looking for everybody to make a contribution. Group discussion: Who would win StudyTopic or a fly? Who would win StudyTopic or a tree? Who would win StudyTopic or a dolphin. Who would win StudyTopic or Harry Potter? Who would win StudyTopic or a Chemist? After asking and displaying each question you need to justify your answers: Why do you think that? Who agrees and who disagrees? Why? [2 minutes per question. 10 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>282</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Your Opinion</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss your opinion regarding a StudyTopic statement. Emotions may run high during this exercise, I want you to focus on keeping your arguments rational. Look at this (controversial StudyTopic) statement on the board. What do you think of it? Groups of 2. You have 3 minutes to come up with your response [3 mins]. Discussion of responses from different groups. What did you decide? How did you come up with that? What are your reasons for saying that? [10 mins]. Controversial statement: &apos;Only rich people should be allowed access to StudyTopic.&apos; I will randomly pick someone to tell us: What is your reply? x4 [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>283</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Draw: Concept Map</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a concept map of StudyTopic. This task will give you a profound insight into StudyTopic. Groups of 2. On the board is a list of 10 words related to StudyTopic. Your job is to turn these into a &apos;map&apos; of connected words. You need to be able to explain and justify each connection that you make. I will model an example concept map so you know exactly what I am looking for [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>284</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Draw: Venn Diagram</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a Venn Diagram about StudyTopic. This is going to get you thinking about the different aspects of StudyTopic. Groups of 4. Think about all of the different aspects of StudyTopic, make a list of 10 [3 mins]. Choose two different aspects and using two ropes in the shape of circles make a life-size Venn Diagram of StudyTopic [demonstrate to students]. Label your diagram using words written on A4 paper [5 mins]. Share Venn diagrams as a class [5 mins]. Extension: Now think about how you can add a third rope and label each of the additional sections [4 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>285</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Empathize: Themes And Meaning</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to empathize with the themes and meaning of StudyTopic. Today we are going to be considering how we relate to StudyTopic. Look at the StudyTopic: Poem, Piece of Art, Sculpture, Picture or Prop. What themes do you think are involved in StudyTopic? You have 1 minute to think about your answers, then I am going to randomly select someone to share their thoughts x3 [1 min]. We are going to have a class discussion and in that I want you to think and empathize about the themes that we have looked at [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>286</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Evaluate: Impoptance Pyramid</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to evaluate the most important quality of StudyTopic. Groups of 3. Discuss: What do you think are the 5 most important qualities of StudyTopic? [3 mins]. Narrow your 5 down to the 3 most important qualities of StudyTopic [2 mins]. Now narrow the 3 down to the most important quality of StudyTopic [1 min]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>287</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Exercise: Bodies</Title>
<Details>Objective: To wake up our bodies and get blood circulating to our brains. To help to wake-up our brains we are going to do some exercises: Stand up. Stretch as high as you can, try to touch the ceiling. Jog on the spot. Reach for your toes. Stand up straight. Circle your arms forwards. And backwards. One arm forwards and one arm backwards. Switch the other way. Pat your tummy and rub your head. [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>288</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Explain Why: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to explain our answers to questions about StudyTopic. This is going to whip up a frenzied interest in StudyTopic. We are going to have a discussion about StudyTopic [2 minutes per question]. The first question is: Does StudyTopic matter? Why should we bother to respect StudyTopic? Will knowing about StudyTopic ever be useful for you? What is the point to StudyTopic? What things are connected to StudyTopic? In what ways might knowing about StudyTopic be useful? [12 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>289</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Explore: Uses</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to explore the ways in which power and StudyTopic are used in society. This is going to stimulate thinking about the bigger picture of StudyTopic. Groups of 4. Using your keywords ‘explore’, ‘power’, ‘StudyTopic’, ‘society’ (a different one for each group) come up with as many related words as you can think of [1 min]. Discussion: What related words did you come up with? How are those words different? What is their meaning? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>290</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Filter: Questions - 5,3,1</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to filter down to one StudyTopic question that you would like to answer today. Today we will begin studying StudyTopic, shortly you are going to be prioritizing what you want to work on. First write down 5 questions you would like answered [4 mins]. Now decide on 3 questions [2 mins]. Now decide on what you think is the most important question [1 min]. Discussion: How did you make your decision? Why did you decide on the final question? [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>291</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Form: Freeze Frame</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to form a Freeze Frame about StudyTopic. This is going to involve you using your most imaginative acting skills. Together we are going to identify the different areas/parts of StudyTopic. Write up class thoughts on the board: What are the different aspects of StudyTopic? What do each of them involve [5 mins]? Groups of 4. Your task is to choose one of the areas of StudyTopic that we have written up on the board and produce a freeze frame that shows it [4 mins]. The groups are going to take it in turns to show their freeze frames. We (the class) ape going to interpret the freeze frame and then identify the different parts of StudyTopic that we can see [6 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>292</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Form: Sentences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to form sentences about StudyTopic. For this you are going to need to work together as a class. Everyone has got a word on a piece of colored card. Your task is to get together in groups and arrange yourself so as to spell out the sentence correctly. [students form sentences, allow students to work out that the same colored card needs to be together in the same group] Now I am going to give you a bigger bit of card, this time it has a sentence on it. Your task this time is to compose a paragraph [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>293</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Formulate: Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to formulate questions about StudyTopic. Put on your interrogation hats for the start of this exercise. Look at the StudyTopic material (Pictures, Poems, Articles, Facts, Extracts and Experiment Results) around the classroom [3 mins]. Think about what you have seen and read. Write a list of 5 questions you want to  answer by the end of this lesson [3 mins]. Looking back to the stimulus material at the start try to write 3 more questions about what you would like to answer by the end of the unit [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>294</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Groupings: Keywords</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to group StudyTopic keywords. For this you&apos;ll need to work together and work quickly, get ready. Look at the register of names projected on the board. Next to your name is one of 5 keywords for StudyTopic. You have 5 seconds to remember your word [pause]. Today we are studying StudyTopic. Your task is to get into a group with all 5 of the keywords for today&apos;s lesson. When you have done that you need to decide which is the most important and why [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>295</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Identify: Differences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify the differences between StudyTopic and something else. You&apos;ll need to think carefully and look closely for this task. Groups of 2. Look at the 2 words (StudyTopic, ConceptX). What do you think are the similarities between StudyTopic and ConceptX? What do you think are the differences between StudyTopic and ConceptX? [Students discuss and then feedback] Now look at the 2 pictures (StudyTopic, ConceptY). What do you think are the similarities between StudyTopic and ConceptY? What do you think are the differences between StudyTopic and ConceptY?  [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>296</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Identify: Facts And Opinions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify StudyTopic facts and opinions. In this task it is very hard to spot all of the facts and all of the opinions. Read through this newspaper article about StudyTopic. Your task is to highlight anything you think is a fact in green and anything that you think is an opinion in orange [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>297</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Identify: Keywords</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify StudyTopic keywords starting with different letters. Everyone must say at least one word during this first bit of lesson. Claqs in 4 groups. When I say a letter you respond with a key word related to StudyTopic that begins with that letter. In this activity there is no writing allowed. What we will do is cycle through the 4 groups. You will score 4 points for a good word said quickly, 3 for fairly quickly, 2 for slow to respold and 1 for a slowly given poor word [2 mins]. You now have 2 minutes to look up and revise StudyTopic words [2 mins]. We will now continue with our keywords exercise [4 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>298</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Identify: Lesson Focus</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify what I will focus on at the start of the lesson. This will get you thilking. Identify which of the following is the correct way to spend the first part of the lesson: A. I should make my work as neat as possible. B, I should count the exact number of words I have written. C. I should use the time to do some mmre writing. D. I should read through my work and check that I have met all of the success criteria.[5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>299</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Identify: Meaning</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify the meaning of StudyTopic. What is the significance of StudyTopic? Everybody is connected to StudyTopic in one way or another.&apos; What does it mean? In what ways is it true? In what ways is it not true? Can you explain it to someone else? Your task is to answer these questions and write your own explanation of the statement’s meaning [8 mins]. Share answers [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>300</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Identify: Noises</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify StudyTopic noises. Clean out your ears! Listen to this noise [play StudyTopic related noise 1...]. What do you think the noise is? What might we be learning about in today&apos;s lesson? Listen to this noise [play StudyTopic related noise 2...]. What do you think the noise is? How do you think that is connected to StudyTopic? Listen to this noise [play StudyTopic related noise 3...]. What do you think the noise is? How is that connected to StudyTopic? [5 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>301</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Improvements: Corrections</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make improvements to your StudyTopic work. Kaizen is the Japanese word for continuous improvement and it is a great way to develop. Your first task is to read through the last piece of work  and read the comments that have been written [2 mins]. Your second task is correct and improve the work: Add in more detail, correct any spelling mistakes, carry out the extension question. Ask yourself8 Have I fully answered the question as best as I can? What would make this a better piece of work? What can I add to really show that I understand what we have learnt? [5 mins] Read through the criteria which will be used to mark your work: Neatness of Writing 20%, Correct Spelling 20%, Well Written Answer 30%, Comprehensive Answer 30%. What do you think should be your mark for your work? Write down your percentage for each of the criteria [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>302</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Link: Character</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to link a character to StudyTopic. Dress up (or ask a student to dress up) as a character related to StudyTopic (via a country, concept, text, discovery). Your first task is to guess who I am [2 mins]. What do you think the link is to StudyTopic? Why is this person important [4 mins]? Here is a bag of props relating to our StudyTopic character. I am going to pick people to come and take out one prop and make some guesses about the detail of the character [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>303</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Link: Nouns</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to link StudyTopic to different nouns and explain why they are linked. To start today&apos;s StudyTopic lesson I&apos;d like to write down 10 random nouns on the board. They can be any nouns at all. I will ask specific students and I will write up what you say onto the board [3 mins]. The 5 StudyTopic Keywords for today are..... You have 5 milutes to complete 5 creative sentences using the noun words and today&apos;s keywords: ______ is like (a) ______ because ______ (StudyTopic Keyword, Noun, Reason). For example: (Photosynthesis) is like a (Waterwheel) because (as carbon dioxide is broken down energy is converted from one form to another) [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>304</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>List: A-Z</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to list a StudyTopic word for each letter of the alphabet. How many letters are there in the alphabet?(26) Your task is to write down a word related to StudyTopic for each of those letters. If you cannot think of one for a letter then go to the next one. You have 8 minutes, that is 18 seconds per letter. Go! [8 mins]. Which 2 learners have written down the largest number of words? Read out your words [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>305</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>List: Associations</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to list all of the words you associate with StudyTopic. List all the words you associate with StudyTopic. Which 2 people have the most StudyTopic words? (Read Out) [4 mins]. Now join all of those words together to make your own definition for StudyTopic. (Read out definitions) [4 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>306</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>List: Products</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make a list of products that are used in and use StudyTopic. Make a list of products that are used in StudyTopic [2 mins]. Make a list of products that use StudyTopic [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>307</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Mark: Homework</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to correctly assess and mark homework. By engaging in the process of StudyTopic assessment you will gain a deeper understanding; of StudyTopic, of &apos;what learning is&apos; and you will begin to think about desirable qualities in your own work. Groups of 2. Your task is to write out a mark scheme for the work that you have done. You need to have 4 criteria. For each criteria explain what you think a good piece of work looks like, what a satisfactory piece of work looks like and what a bad piece of work looks like [5 mins]. Your task is to self (or peer) - mark the class homework using your student-made mark-scheme. For each of your criteria explain why you have given the mark you have. Then write on one comment as to how you could improve the next piece of work you do [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>308</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Meaning: My Word!</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to give the meaning of different StudyTopic words. 2 students are going come around and they are going to give you a StudyTopic word. Have a look at your word because in a moment you will have to stand up and give the meaning. You will then choose the next person who will give the meaning of their word [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>309</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Model: Play Doh</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to model StudyTopic using play doh. Groups of 4. Your task is to make a model of the StudyTopic word (using Play Doh). Your word is secret and only your group are allowed to know it. To help keep your word secret you are only allowed to communicate by writing. You have 10 minutes to make your model [10 mins]. Now you have 5 minutes to look at the different models and write down what you think each group&apos;s word is [2 mins]. Split the Play Doh from your model so that each person has a piece. Make a quick model which shows either of these two things: &apos;What I would like to learn about StudyTopic.&apos; or &apos;How I would like to change through learning about StudyTopic&apos; [2 mins]. Extension: What skills will I use and improve studying StudyTopic? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>310</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Perform: Death By ..</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to perform a 1 minute play about StudyTopic. Groups of 4. Your task is come up with two different 1 minute plays in which a person dies because of StudyTopic. In 10 minutes time we will watch one of your plays [10 mins]. We will randomly choose 3 of the groups tm perform their plays [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>311</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Perform: Television Talent Show</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to perform on a StudyTopic Television Talent Show. We are going to play StudyTopic Television Talent Show (America&apos;s Got Talent, X Factor,..). Your task is to come on stage (an area of the classroom) and use all 10 of today&apos;s keywords. You will be given a score out of 10 for your eloquence and the passion of your performance. You have 5 minutes to prepare [5 mins]. Now we will randomly choose 5 students from the register to perform. Performances [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>312</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Position: For And Against</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to give your position for or against StudyTopic. Arrange yourselves in a line. Strongly for StudyTopic at this end and strongly against StudyTopic at the other end [2 mins]. Can you explain why you have chosen to stand here? What are your feelings about StudyTopic? [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>313</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Present: The News</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to present a StudyTopic news story. Groups of 2. You are news presenters. You are going to speai a one minute piece to camera [can be a pretend camera] that introduces StudyTopic. You have 10 minutes to prepare and then you will perform to the class. Think about the structure of what a News Presenter says: Dramatic Introduction, Why it&apos;s important, The message you want to get across, A funny summary line to finish [10 mins]. Present news stories [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>314</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Question: Mystery Person</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to ask questions to identify the mystery StudyTopic person. One student receives a card with a famous StudyTopic figure and some biographical details on it. We are going to question this important StudyTopic figure (to strictly &apos;yes&apos;, &apos;no&apos; or &apos;don&apos;t know&apos; responses) to ascertain who they are [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>315</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Redesign: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to redesign StudyTopic. How would you redesign StudyTopic? Then challenge students by setting parameters. How could you redesign StudyTopic to make it more effective? How could you redesign StudyTopic to make it easier to use? [Discussion 5 mins] Using play doh, newspaper, cardboard and paper make a model of what redesigned StudyTopic look like [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>316</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Reflection: Meta Learning Starter</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on learning about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. With your partner discuss the following questions: What do you want to learn about StudyTopic? What skills do you have that would assist you in learning about StudyTopic? What might hinder your thinking about StudyTopic? When have you had to think about StudyTopic before? What have you learnt that is similar to StudyTopic? What do you already know that might be useful in learning about StudyTopic? What must you do in this lesson? What could you do in this lesson? What should you do in this lesson? [10 mins]. Class discussion: What do we think will be distractions to us learning about StudyTopic? How do we avoid them? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>317</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Relate: Picture Uncover</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to relate the parts of a picture to StudyTopic. Look at the (partial StudyTopic) picture on the board. Can you guess what it is yet? Take a guess as to what you think it is. [Take guesses from students]. I am going to uncover a bigger section and I will give you another opportunity to have a guess. How is the StudyTopic picture related to what we will be learning today? What is/are StudyTopic? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>318</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Review: 5 Sentences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write 5 sentences that review our work from the last lesson. Write down 5 of the words that we studied during last lesson [Allow 3 mins]. For each of your words write one sentence correctly using the word [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>319</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Review: Just A Minute</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to talk for 60 seconds about the last lesson. Review of last lesson. Your challenge is to speak for 1 minute about what we studied last lesson. You are not allowed to: Hesitate (Pause or say &apos;erm&apos;), Repeat or Make A Mistake. You have 5 minutes to prepare [5 mins]. [randomly choose 3 students] At the first repetition, pause or mistake I will say &apos;Next&apos; and the next student takes over. We will carry on until the minute is up. Count how many times &apos;Next&apos; is said. Repeat with another 2 groups of 3 students [5 mins]. The group with the fewest &apos;Nexts&apos; are the winners. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>320</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Say: Sentences With Voice</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to say sentences about StudyTopic using different voices. We need 2 volunteers. The winner is the person that can say: &apos;StudyTopic Sentence A&apos; the loudest. [repeat using a new sentence, 2 new randomly chosen students and the next method of saying the sentence]. Methods: Who can say this StudyTopic sentence in the loudest voice? Who can say this StudyTopic sentence the quietest? Who can say this StudyTopic sentence the slowest? Who can say this StudyTopic sentence in the quickest? Who can say this StudyTopic sentence in the deepest voice? Who can say this StudyTopic sentence in the highest pitched voice? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>321</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Sculpt: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make a sculpture of StudyTopic. Groups of 3 (using numbers). Your task is to sculpt the lesson objective(s) for today&apos;s lesson. To help you there are some materials (i.e., cardboard, coat-hangers, string). There are some specific success criteria that I will put on the board: 100% all objective(s) accurately reflected in the model. 80% most objectives(s) reflected. 60% part of the objective(s) missing. Get going [10 mins]. Have you met 100% of the success criteria? Join with another group and assess each others work [3 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>322</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Set: Goals</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to set goals for learning StudyTopic. Today you are going to set your own goals for the lesson. In your book create a table with two columns ald four rows. In the two columns write: Know about StudyTopic. And: Want to know about StudyTopia. Now fill in your table with 4 things you Know and 4 things you Want to Know [5 mins]. Write 2 sentences explaining how you will go about learning what you have written in Want to know. What techniques will you use? What information do you need to look at? [3 mins] Share your thoughts with two other students [2 mins]. [Plenary - Revisit at the end of the lesson. 2 minutes per questions] Write down - What 4 things you have Learnt about StudyTopic? What you found easy about StudyTopic? What have you found difficult about StudyTopic? What would you like to learn in the future (with respect to StudyTopic)? [8 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>323</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Share: Ideas And Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to share ideas and questions about StudyTopic. Write down: 3 things I know about StudyTopic. 2 questions I have about StudyTopic. 1 thing that StudyTopic is like and why. [5 mins] Discussion: What questions do you have? What are the things you know? What do you think StudyTopic is like? Why? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>324</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Share: Think Pairs</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to share thoughts about StudyTopic. On the board is an open-ended question about StudyTopic. Thinking about the question write down your own ideas and thoughts [3 mins]. Groups of 2. Discuss you answer with your partner [2 mins]. Taking into account what you have discussed write an improvement of your original answer [2 mins]. Compare with your partner again, what are the differences now? [1 min]. Class discussion: How have our ideas changed? Were our original ideas wrong? [3 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>325</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Creative Thinker</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of creative thinker. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is creative thinker. For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Imagine new possibilities? Invent a new way of thinking about StudyTopic? Explore StudyTopic ideas? Adapt ideas about StudyTopic? Persevere? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>326</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Effective Participator</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of effective participator. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is effective participator. For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Discuss? Made proposals? Influence others? Present? Share and communicate? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>327</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Independent Inquirer</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of independent inquirer. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is independent inquirer. For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Asked questions? Research? Selected information? Analyze information? Evaluate information? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>328</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Leadership</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of leadership. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is leadership. For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Inspire others? Take responsibility? Encourage others? Show initiative? Take the lead? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>329</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Reflective Learner</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of reflective learner. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is reflective learner. For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Set goals? Assess yourself? Review and improve your StudyTopic work? Invite feedback? Solve problems? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>330</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Self Manager</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of self manager. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is self manager.  For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Seek out challenges? Be organized? Manage your time? Respond positively? Manage your emotions? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>331</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Skill: Team worker</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to develop the skill of team worker. The skill that we will be focusing on in this StudyTopic lesson is team worker. For each of the following write down 1 example of the ways in which you could: Negotiate? Reach agreement? Support others? Learn from others? Take on roles and responsibility? [5 mins]. Before the end of the lesson we will come back to review whether you were able to carry out any of your ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>332</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Solve: Problem TPS</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to solve a problem using Think, Pair, Share. Give students a problem or question and then allow think time in which they can engage with it. Following this, students turn to their &apos;Learning Partner&apos; and discuss, clarify, challenge, etc. The pair then share with another pair or the whole class (students share their partner&apos;s ideas as well as their own) </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>333</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>State: 10 Words</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to state 10 words related to StudyTopic. When I call your name I want you to give me 10 words related to StudyTopic. X5 [4 mins]. Discuss: What do we think the relationship is between these words? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>334</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>State: Your Opinion</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to state your opinion about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. I am inviting you to speak to the class for 30 seconds and give your opinions of what you think StudyTopic is. You have got 5 minutes to prepare during which time you can write some notes down if you think that might help you [5 mins]. I will randomly pick someone to tell us: What’s your opinion? x4 [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>335</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Summarize: 5 Pictures</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize your thoughts about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Look at the 5 pictures which show the 5 key ideas in StudyTopic. For each picture come up with 3 sentences that summarize your thoughts about StudyTopic [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>336</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Summarize: Caption</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize a StudyTopic picture in 3 sentences. Look at this StudyTopic picture. You have 3 minutes to write an imaginative 3 sentence caption that summarizes what is going on. Go! [3 mins]. Make improvements: What words might be better ones to use? Which ones could you replace to make your sentences sound better? [1 min]. Find 3 people to share your sentences with [2 mins]. Think of a fourth sentence to add to your summary [1 min]. Make a caption for a second picture [6 mins]. https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B4-4CsrIfSBoNk1rWGpBLXRxeWs</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>337</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Summarize: Last Lesson</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize what was learnt during the last lesson. Your task is to make a summary od last lesson. Your summary can be either: A Newspaper Report, A 60-Second News-Flash or A Mime. You have got 5 minutes to prepare and then we will present to the class [5 mins]. Present to the class [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>338</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Take Notes: Press Conference</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to take notes about StudyTopic. I am calling a press conference. There is an announcement to make. You will need to take notes and then ask question about what I say. &apos;Today I am announcing that StudyTopic is being released. It will be available with immediate effect...&apos; [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>339</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Teach: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to teach about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. In 10 minutes time you are going to become the teacher. Your objective is to summarize the last lesson that we had. You also need to question the class on what was studied. To help you do that, write down 3 questions about StudyTopic [10 mins]. I am going to pick a group out of a hat to choose which groups will be teaching. Groups teach and ask their questions x3 [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>340</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Transcribe: That Tune!</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to transcribe a part of a StudyTopic song. Listen to 1 minute of this (StudyTopic themed) song and write down the lyrics as exactly as you can. [play song] I&apos;ll play it a second time so you can check [2 mins]. Look at the lyrics (on the board), highlight anywhere that you have missed or added words. Look carefully at the spelling, highlight any spelling errors (practicing listening, writing and paying attention). What is meant by X? Why is there a problem of X? What can be done to improve the situation of X? [Use the words and ideas in the song to initiate a discussion. 8 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>341</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Translate: Code</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to translate a coded message about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Both of you are going to have an alphabet Morse Code and alphabet Sign Language sheet (students choose which to use). A&apos;s will have second sheet with a StudyTopic question and answer, it is your job to try and communicate your information in code. B&apos;s you are going to try and translate the message [5 mins]. Now swap for a different StudyTopic question and answer sheet and repeat [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>342</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>View: Different Shoes</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to view StudyTopic from different perspectives. I want to invite you to change your shoes and look at things from a different view... &apos;If Brad Pitt was put in charge of StudyTopic what would change?&apos; &apos;If Hilary Clinton was managing StudyTopic, what would she focus on?&apos; Choose a celebrity and write a paragraph about what StudyTopic would be like if they were in control of it. Give some examples using different aspects of StudyTopic [10 mins]. Read aloud paragraphs [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>343</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Warm Up: Eights</Title>
<Details>Before we start studying StudyTopic this is a fantastic way to get you body moving and your blood pumping to your brain. Find yourself a space in the classroom and stand up straight and relaxed. Make an Eight movement with your left big toe. Now your left foot. Now your whole left leg. Now repeat with right toe, then foot, then leg. Repeat with left index finger, left hand, left lower arm, left arm. Repeat with right finger, then hand, then arm. Try both arms. In opposite directions. Make Eight-shaped movements with your pelvis. Try horizontally and vertically. Try to change direction. Now try your left shoulder, right shoulder and both shoulders. Make an Eight with your head. To finish try to make Eights simultaneously with as many parts of your body as you can [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>344</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Write:  A Song</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a song about StudyTopic. Your task is to write a song explaining what you already know about StudyTopic. You can you choose which genre your song will be: rap, country, pop or blues [10 mins]. We will randomly choose somebody to share their song x 4 [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>345</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Write: Questions From Answers</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a question when starting with a StudyTopic keyword as the answer. If this is the answer, then what&apos;s the question? If the answer is: Frog The question could be: What&apos;s green and jumps? Now look at these 5 StudyTopic words, your task is to come up with a question that lets you identify each of them. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>346</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Write: Recipe</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a recipe to make StudyTopic. What is a recipe? Your task is to write out a recipe to make your favorite food (e.g., pizza), [2 mins]. Have you fully explained how to make your food? Could you have made a more detailed recipe? Today we are going to be studying StudyTopic. Your task is to write a comprehensive recipe to make StudyTopic, make sure that you include everything you need. In 10 minutes we will read out our recipes [10 mins]. Read out recipes [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>347</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Write: Slogans</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write slogans about StudyTopic. StudyTopic is power&apos; is an example of a slogan. A slogan summarizes your thoughts and feelings about a particular thing. There are two techniques to help you think of a slogan. The first is to think of an image that sums up StudyTopic for you. What are its qualities? What does it feel like? The second is to not censor your thoughts, just write down what you think of. You have 5 minutes to create a slogan about StudyTopic and then we will read out what we have come up with [5 mins]. We’ll randomly choose a student to share their slogan x 4 [10 mins].  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>348</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Write: SOC</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a stream of consciousness about StudyTopic. To start us on our StudyTopic lesson I&apos;d like to do a stream of consciousness spider diagram. Groups of 2. On the bit of paper (one between two people) write down your thoughts for the 5 StudyTopic words on the board [2 mins]. Now using those words come up with one or two sentences to summarize your thoughts about StudyTopic. You do not need to write anything doun as we will share our thoughts [2 mins]. Let’s look at what we came up with: Class discussion [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>349</ID>
<Section>Starter</Section>
<Title>Write: Word Fill</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a StudyTopic word fill. On the board there are 2 sentences with missing words. Your task is find the words to complete the sentence: BLANK is important because it is BLANK in... (StudyTopic, Used). BLANK can be found on BLANK BLANK. (StudyTopic, Planet Earth) [3 mins]. In your own words writes a paragraph to explain what the sentences mean [5 mins]. Create your own missing words sentence for StudyTopic [5 mins]. Share missing words sentences with the class [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>350</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Activity</Title>
<Details>Groups of 2. You have 20 minutes to complete this assignment. Your StudyTopic assignment is to </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>351</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Not Appropriate</Title>
<Details>A main activity is not appropriate to the structure of this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>352</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Act Out: A Story</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to act out a story about StudyTopic. I am going to choose five volunteers who will act out the StudyTopic story, each volunteer is going to have a role [allocate roles]. While I read the (StudyTopic) story the volunteers are going to listen and then act according to what is happening [model an example]. Read story [3 mins]. With a partner retell what has happened in the story [3 mins]. Now we are going to write down as much as we can remember [5 mins]. Imagine one picture which summarizes the story for you, what does it look like? Draw your picture [5 mins]. Looking back over the (StudyTopic) story try to write five questions about what happened (and underneath write the answers) [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>353</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Act Out: Comedy</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to act out a comedy scene about StudyTopic. Groups of 3. Your task is to create and then act out a StudyTopic comedy scene. Choose 5 StudyTopic words to include in your scene [10 mins]. Act out each of the scenes [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>354</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Act Out: Scene</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to act out an everyday scene and include StudyTopic. You are going to act out a scene. The scene can be anywhere you want: A Living Room, A Restaurant or A Shop. In the scene you must include 5 StudyTopic words from today&apos;s lesson. You have 10 minutes to prepare [10 mins]. Performances [10 mins]. Make a second scene that, contains comedy or is serious [5 mins]. Performances [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>355</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Analyze: Article</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to analyze an article about StudyTopic. Read the StudyTopic article [4 mins]. What are the underlying assumptions in the StudyTopic article? Go through and highlight the assumptions. I will show you the first one [4 mins]. Look through the assumptions you have highlighted and answer these questions: Are they fair assumptions to maie about StudyTopic? Why or why not? Justify your answer [10 mins]. We&apos;ll now share our thoughts about the article. We are going to randomly select someone to read aloud their writing and then ask another student if they agree or disagree and why x3 [8 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>356</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Analyze: Before And After</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to analyze the historical impact of StudyTopic. You are going to pick a point in history and compare life before StudyTopic with life after StudyTopic. Think about the concept /idea /invention /discovery. Document your thoughts in an essay [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>357</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Analyze: SWOT</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to carry out a SWOT analysis about StudyTopic. Groups of 4. Each person in the group needs to come up with 3 ideas for each of the areas of the SWOT analysis. What are the Strengths of StudyTopic? What are the Weaknesses of StudyTopic? What Opportunities does StudyTopic present? What Threats does StudyTopic present? [20 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>358</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Answer: Question</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer the question about StudyTopic. Think about the StudyTopic question from the beginning of the lesson. Your task is to use what you have learnt to answer the StudyTopic question. Your answer could be; written (max 200 words), still image, poster or a storyboard (all with detailed annotations). Your answer needs to make it clear who your audiences is [10 mins]. I am going to choose a student to show and read out their answer. The rest of us are going to listen carefully and then feedback by; writing a comment using a mini-whiteboard, thumbs/colops agreement. x4 [6 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>359</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Answer: Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer the questions about StudyTopic. Read through the passages in the textbook about StudyTopic [5 mins]. Discuss as a class [3 mins]. Answer all of the questions in the text book and then answer the questions on the worksheets. Use full sentences for your answers [10 mins]. As a class we will go through the answers to the first set of questions and I will clarify any misunderstandings [3 mins]. Continue answering the second set of questions [10 mins]. As a class we will go through the answers to the second set of questions and I will clarify any misunderstandings [3 mins]. Draw an illustration of StudyTopic, adding color and labels [10 mins].  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>360</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Debate: (Silently)</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to have a silent debate about StudyTopic. Groups of 2 (AB). A&apos;s, you are going to argue in favor of StudyTopic. B&apos;s, you are going to argue against StudyTopic. The one rule is that this is a &apos;Silent Debate&apos;. That means you are only allowed to communicate by writing your ideas onto the shared piece of paper. When your opponent writes an argument try to write your own counter argument [5 mins]. Swap partners and carry on [5 mins]. Swap partners and carry on [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>361</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Debate: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to debate StudyTopic. Class in 2 teams. Today we are going to conduct a debate about StudyTopic. This side of the room is going to argue for StudyTopic. This side of the room is going to argue against StudyTopic. You have 5 minutes to prepare your arguments using these 2 textbooks and 2 information sheets [5 mins]. Debate [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>362</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Design: A Game</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design a game about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Your task is to design and make a board game that uses StudyTopic concepts and keywords. You might have that each time a player answers a question they can move their game piece. You can really use your imagination, you have 20 minutes to make your games [20 minute]. Groups of 4. Choose one of your group&apos;s games and play it [5 mins]. I will collect these in because we will continue with the other games at the start of the next lesson [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>363</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Design: An Advert</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design an advertisement for StudyTopic. What do you think makes for a good advertisement? What is an example of a good billboard advert? Discussion [3 mins]. Your assignment is to design al advertisement that promotes StudyTopic. Think about the qualities of StudyTopic that you can include. Your advert needs to have a description, a price and a slogan. You have 20 minutes [20 mins]. Layout your work around the classroom and take one sticky note. Write your name on the sticky note. You are going to choose one of the pieces of work and write on the sticky note one thing that is good about the work and one thing that could be improved [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>364</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Design: Media Cover</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design a media cover for a StudyTopic product. Discussion: What image summarizes StudyTopic for you, explain your answer? [2 mins]. Your task is to design an MP3 Image, eBook Cover, or e-magazine cover about StudyTopic [15 mins]. Write a paragraph that explains the different image elements you have drawn. What does each aspect represent? How is each part of your drawing connected to StudyTopic? [5 mins]. Students look at each others work and explain their thinking [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>165</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Draw: Cartoon Strip</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a cartoon strip about StudyTopic. Your task is to create a cartoon strip and illustrate one of the StudyTopic concepts we have covered. Your cartoon strip must have at least 5 pictures and each picture must have one dialogue bubble containing at least one StudyTopic word [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>366</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Draw: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw StudyTopic. Your task is to create a drawing/ painting/ illustration that shows StudyTopic. Put StudyTopic into an interesting setting. How can you display StudyTopic so that you can show all of its different aspects? [20 mins]. Write a paragraph that explains your drawing (like the ones in an art gallery). Is there any subtle meaning in your work? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>367</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Draw: Timeline</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a timeline of StudyTopic. Your task is to draw a timeline of events that occurred during the discovery/ development of StudyTopic. Your timeline should have 5 events. Write a paragraph for each of the events. You have 5 minutes to research StudyTopic and 15 minutes to produce your timeline [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>368</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Elect: Class Brain</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to elect the StudyTopic class brain. Listen carefully to this (election) speech. Today we are having an election for the &apos;StudyTopic Claqs Brain&apos;. Your task is to write a speech by using as many StudyTopic words as you can think of. You have 10 minutes before we will hear the speeches [10 mins]. Now we’ll read 6 speeches that you have written and then we’ll have a alass vote for the ‘StudyTopic Class Brain’ [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>369</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Exchange: Information</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to exchange information about StudyTopic. [Give each student 1 of 8 pieces of StudyTopic information] You are not allowed to show anyone else your information. You are allowed to refer back to it if you need to check what it says. Your task is to talk to as many students as you can and fill in this grid (A4 8 square grid) so that you know the full StudyTopic story [10 mins]. Using the information you have collected write a paragraph about StudyTopic and draw a diagram (with labels) to illustrate the concepts involved [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>370</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Explain: To An Alien</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to explain StudyTopic to an alien. Imagine that an alien has just arrived on planet earth. She has absolutely no ideas about StudyTopic. What is StudyTopic used for? Where is StudyTopic used? Why is StudyTopic used? Write a 4 page booklet &apos;An Aliens Guide To StudyTopic&apos; which fully explains StudyTopic [30 mins]. Read through your alien explanation, do you: use precise language, put in enough detail, have alear explanations [5 mins]?</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>371</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Explain: With A Poster</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make a poster that explains StudyTopic. Groups of 4. You have 15 minutes to create an information poster about StudyTopic [15 mins]. Label yourselves ‘A’ ‘B’ ‘C’ and ‘D’ [1 min]. A&apos;s and B&apos;s will remain with the poster and explain what you have done. C&apos;s and D&apos;s have 2 minutes to walk around and look at the other posters  [2 mins]. C&apos;s and D&apos;s you now have 2 minutes to feedback what you found out [2 mins]. To finish off we are now going to write one paragraph about what we have found out [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>372</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Fill: Display Board</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to fill a display board with StudyTopic work. Working individually; you are going to make a/an StudyTopic classroom display poster that will replace the old work on this display board. Your StudyTopic poster must have: correct spelling, be at least A4 size, have at least 2 sentences and 1 picture. You have 20 minutes [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>373</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Form: A Company</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to form a company to make money from StudyTopic. Groups of 2. You are going to create a company that exploits StudyTopic. Your task is to create a brief that explains what your company does and how it makes money. You will present your ideas at the end of the class [20 mins]. I will randomly choose 2 of the groups to present their companies [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>374</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Gather: Put It Back Together</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to gather information about StudyTopic. Each of you have 1 of 5 different StudyTopic information cards. You are not allowed to let anyone else see your card but you are allowed to read it out. You have got 10 minutes to get notes on all of the information cards. Go [10 minutes}. Now get yourselves into groups of 2 and share what you&apos;ve found out [2 mins]. Now join together with another group and share what you found [3 mins]. To summarize write one paragraph explaining what you found out [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>375</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Graph: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to collect data about StudyTopic and then draw an appropriate graph. This activity will give you a clear visual understanding of StudyTopic. First you will need to collect the data about StudyTopic [5 mins]. Now you are going to decide on the appropriate graph (line, bar, scatter or pie chart). Think about the things you need to do: Work in pencil and use a ruler. Give your graph a title. Use appropriately sized axis. Label your axis is. Highlight any anomalous results [10 mins]. Swap your work with the person next to you. How well have they done? Give them one mark for each criteria [2 mins]. Make a graph of this second set of data (data handout) [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>376</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Identify: Benefits/ Drawbacks</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify the benefits and drawbacks of different aspects of StudyTopic. What are the benefits and the drawbacks of StudyTopic? Consider the impact of StudyTopic on the country as a whole and on the local area. You must write a minimum of 400 words and cite at least 2 sources [15 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>377</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Identify: Word Define</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify and define StudyTopic keywords. We are going to watch a video clip and then listen to an audio clip about StudyTopic. Take a look at the list of words on the board. During the clips you are going to listen out for those words. When you hear the word write down how it was used and your own definition of the word (pause if necessary) [15 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>378</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Imagine: A Wedding</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to imagine the marriage of StudyTopic. Imagine that StudyTopic was going to get married. Who or what would StudyTopic get married to? How would StudyTopic complement their partner? What and who would be at their wedding? What would their wedding be like? Write a description of the wedding. [10 mins]. Share with your partner what you have come up with [2 mins]. Write out what their wedding vows would be. Describe if they were to have children what their children would be like. [10 mins]. Share as a class 3 of the wedding descriptions [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>379</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Interview: Job Application</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to carry out and take part in a StudyTopic intepview. Write a StudyTopic job application form. What would someone doing the job of StudyTopic need to be able tm do? [10 mins]. Groups of 2 (AB). A&apos;s you will receive a sheet with information about StudyTopic. B&apos;s your job is to interview A&apos;s in order to find out information about StudyTopic [5 mins]. We’ll now listen to feedback from different students in the class [2 mins]. New partners. We are going to do the same thing but this time the interviewer is not allowed to ask closed questions and interviewees must use at least 2 StudyTopic words in their answer [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>380</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Invent: A Machine</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to invent a machine that produces StudyTopic. Invent a machine to produce StudyTopic. You need to think about all the parts of StudyTopic and show in your diagram how your machine will deal with each of them [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>381</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Invent: A Product</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to invent a new StudyTopic product. Your task is to invent a new StudyTopic product. Give it a name and write out and a plan marketing campaign. Your marketing plan needs to: Have an outline of your product and answer the questions: What are the features of your StudyTopic product? Where will you be able to buy your StudyTopic product? Who will your StudyTopic produce appeal to? [15 mins]. I am going to pick people to share their StudyTopic products, let&apos;s start with.....[10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>382</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Make: A Word Fill</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make a set of StudyTopic word fill exercises. Groups of 2. Each group now has (2 different) reading passages, and a thick black pen. First read through your passage, keeping it away from your partner [2 mins]. Now you are going to cross out one word from each sentence. Give each word that you cross out a number and write the crossed out word with the number on a separate answer sheet [model for students. 5 mins]. You have now created an individual word-fill exercise for your partner. Swap sheets and fill in the blanks [5 mins]. Swap back and mark your partners work. Give them a mark and share with them [3 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>383</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Practical: Investigation</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to carry out a practical investigation into StudyTopic. Your task is to carry out a practical investigation into StudyTopic. Investigate the different areas of StudyTopic. Document the results. Draw the results on an appropriate graph. Write a conclusion. Evaluate the practical [20 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>384</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Present: An Interview</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to present an interview about StudyTopic. Your task is to choose to prepare either a Role-Play, A News Report, an Advert or a Radio Interview. Your objective is to creatively demonstrate your knowledge of StudyTopic. You have 15 minutes to prepare and practice your script [15 mins]. Join together with another group and perform your role play. Each person in the other group will give an example of one thing they think is good and one thing they think could be improved, and how [model for students]. Groups perform and feedback to each other [5 minutes]. The best work is selected and shown to the class [10 mins]. Write down 3 things for What Went Well (WWW) and 3 things for Even Better If (EBI) [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>385</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Present: Information</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to present information about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Each group has got a different piece of (StudyTopic) information (drawn from a variety of resources). Using the information your task is to prepare a short presentation about StudyTopic [10 mins]. During the presentation you need to make notes. I will choose 4 students to ask questions to the presenting group. At the end of each presentation I will choose one person to summarize what you have learnt x3 [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>386</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Promote: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to create a promotional campaign for StudyTopic. Not many people are aware of the importance of StudyTopic. Your job is to create a promotional campaign that raises peoples&apos; awareness. What effects does StudyTopic have? Why is StudyTopic important? Try to communicate your ideaq through images to really get the concepts across [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>387</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Re-Tell: Story-Time</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to re-tell a StudyTopic story. Re-tell today&apos;s lesson as a story. Choose your genre: Fantasy, Sci-fi, Thriller or Romance. Your story must have a beginning, a middle and an end [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>388</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Read: Material</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to read material about StudyTopic. We are going to make reading active so that we can really connect with the StudyTopic text. Turn to page 100 and read through individually [2 mins]. Now we’ll read through as a class. At various points I’ll stop and randomly choose someone to answer a question: &apos;What does that mean? Why was it phrased like that? Where else might you find that?  [5 mins]. Your task is to write a heading for each paragraph we have read. Then you are going to turn the heading into a one-sentence summary of the paragraph. This is what that looks like: model desired result. [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>389</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Reflection: Meta Learning Main</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on learning about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. With your partner discuss the following questions: Has any of the lesson been about you? In learning about StudyTopic what connections have you made? How do you feel about StudyTopic? How have you got involved in learning about StudyTopic? What breakthroughs have you made? What must you do to further your learning about StudyTopic? What aspects of StudyTopic do you want to know more about? What are you currently thinking about? [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>390</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Reinterpret: Information</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reinterpret information about StudyTopic. Your task is to reinterpret the StudyTopic Information. You can choose either an annotated poster, a newslettep, an information leaflet [15 mins]. Present your work to the class and explain each part [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>391</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Respond: Newspaper Article</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a response to a newspaper article about StudyTopic. Read through the (StudyTopic) newspaper article [4 mins]. What are your thoughts? What are the opinions that are expressed in the piece? Do you agree or disagree with the opinions? How would you express the ideas in your own words? Write your own response to StudyTopic newspaper article. You must include: A summary of the article, Your opinions and your own solutions to the problems outlined [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>392</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Respond: TV Crew</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to respond to a TV interview about StudyTopic. Groups of 3. A film crew from National Television would like to interview you about StudyTopic. They have asked you to respond to one of 3 statements. Each person in your group should speak about one aspect of what the statement brings up: &apos;The government is proposing to introduce a ban on any discussion about StudyTopic.&apos; &apos;A conspiracy theory has surfaced on the internet which suggests that StudyTopic will the cause of the end of the world.$apos; &apos;StudyTopic is claimed by a leading crystal therapy healer to increase lifespan by 10 years.&apos; You have 10 minutes to prepare your response [10 mins]. Each group performs their response to our (imaginary) TV crew [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>393</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Review: Half Yearly</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to review how well the year has gone. Write a half-yearly report explaining what has gone well during the first half of the year. Outline the 10 main things that have been studied. For each of them say what went well and what could have been better [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>394</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Revise: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to revise StudyTopic. Think about the unit we have studied. On cards write down 5 questions that you know the answers to [5 mins]. On the back of the card write the answer [2 mins]. Choose a partner on the other side of the room and swap your cards and read the other person&apos;s. Repeat x5 [5 mins]. Write down 2 questions that you want to know the answers to and using a textbook look up the answers [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>395</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Seek: Information</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to seek out information about StudyTopic. Look at the information posters about StudyTopic (placed around the room). Your task is to look at and fill up your grid with StudyTopic information. Each box must have something in it and you must write in sentences [10 mins]. Compare the information you have collected with your neighbor. Do you have any differences? Why? [2 mins]. Using your grid write a one page summary of StudyTopic [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>396</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Sort: And Talk</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to sort and prioritize StudyTopic information. Groups of 4. Look at the StudyTopic Cards (Key Words /Phrases /Questions /Pieces of Information). Your task is to place the cards into a diamond shape, with the card you agree with the most at the top, and the least at the bottom (can also be done by importance). You need to come to an agreement as a group and justify and explain your choices [15 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>397</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Substitute: Song Words</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to substitute StudyTopic words within a song. Look at the 8 lines of this song. Your task is to replace words in the song with as many StudyTopic words as you can. You can either use this song or you can do it with your favorite song. In 15 minutes time you will have 30 seconds to share what you have prepared with the class [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>398</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title<Talk: Speed Braining</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to talk about StudyTopic. What is the second most aommon way for singles to meet new people? (speed dating). Today we are going to be doing speed braining! You have 5 minutes to write down 5 good questions about StudyTopic [5 mins]. Arrange your chairs so that they are facing each other. [There will be lots of noise as the class is re-arranged, so use gestures to communicate instructions]. You will have 3 minutes with each person to ask them your questions and give them a mark. When you hear me clap twice we will begin. When I clap again everyone facing the window will move down one. Let&apos;s begin [clap twice] x5 [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>399</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Booklet</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a booklet about StudyTopic. You have 15 minutes to make a booklet to explain the 5 rules you see as important about StudyTopic [15 mins]. You now have 10 minutes to convince two other students why your 5 rules are the most important [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>400</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Children&apos;s Book</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a children&apos;s book about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Think about what it was liie to be 4 years younger than you are. What were the things you inew? What were the things you didn&apos;t know? [2 mins]. Individually: Your taqk is to create &apos;A Children&apos;s Book Of StudyTopic&apos; to help to explain StudyTopic to someone 4 years younger than yourself. The book needs to include problems and answers with workings, as well as picture illustrations [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>401</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Letter To Me</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a letter explaining the principles of StudyTopic. How do you start a formal letter? Address, date, salutation... [2 mins]. Today your task is to write a one page letter to me explaining the principles of StudyTopic [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>402</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Letter To The Head Teacher</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a letter about StudyTopic. Write a letter to your head teacher advising her /him of the changes needed to make StudyTopic more effective. Include your reasons [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>403</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Photo Story</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a StudyTopic story using 6 photos as inspiration. Look at these 6 photos about StudyTopic. Your task is to turn these pictures into a story. You can put the pictures into any order you want. For each picture you must write four sentences. You have 15 minutes to write your story. At the end we&apos;ll read our stories aloud. Let&apos;s get to it [15 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>404</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Request</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a request for greater coverage of StudyTopic. Write a letter to the editor of National News online and request that StudyTopic be given greater coverage. Give 3 different reasons and a persuasive explanation for each [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>405</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: A Speech</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a speech about StudyTopic. Write a persuasive speech which argues either the case for or against StudyTopic. You must show your understanding by mentioning the opposite arguments in your speech. In 15 minutes time we will pick names to read out their speeches [15 mins]. Reading out speeches [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>406</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: An Account</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an account of StudyTopic from different perspectives. Choose 2 perspectives and for each one write a detailed account of StudyTopic. Either: An Environmentalist&apos;s Perspective, An Accountants Perspective, A President&apos;s Perspective, A Communist&apos;s Perspective, A Christian&apos;s Perspective, An Industrialist&apos;s Perspective [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>407</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: An Epitaph</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an epitaph to StudyTopic. Due to a freak occurrence in the space time continuum all StudyTopic has completely vanished from the universe. An epitaph is summary written when a person has died. Write an epitaph for StudyTopic. Who liked StudyTopic? Where was it mostly found? How did StudyTopic positively affect peoples lives? What will life be like without StudyTopic? [15 mins]. I am going to pick a student to read their epitaph (from a bag of student names) x3 [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>408</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: An Essay</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an essay about StudyTopic. Write an essay about StudyTopic. Your essay should include all of the keywords from StudyTopic and explain how they are connected to each other. It needs to have a beginning, a middle and an end. It must thoroughly answer the question (thinking about each of the keywords in the question) [20 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>409</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: An Evaluation</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an evaluation of StudyTopic. Write an evaluation of StudyTopic. What do you think are three good things? What are two bad things about StudyTopic? For each explain why, giving examples [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>410</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Criteria</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write criteria to judge the effectiveness of StudyTopic. Write a list of 5 criteria to judge the effectiveness of StudyTopic. Explain why each one is important and give an example of excellent and poor StudyTopic work for each criteria [20 mins]. Using your 5 criteria you are going to judge some of your previous StudyTopic work [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>411</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Crossword</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a crossword puzzle about StudyTopic. These are 8 StudyTopic words that we are going to be using in today&apos;s lesson. Your first task is to think up a clue for each word. For instance if the word was coal you might say: 4 letters. It is black, found in the ground and burnt as fuel. You need to think up a clue for each of the 8 StudyTopic words [10 mins]. Your second task is to join up your words just like a cross word. Then put a number next to each word. You have created a crossword answer grid. You can draw over the top to create the crossword question grid [5 mins]. Get together with another student and swap crossword puzzles [5 mins]. Extension: Add additional words to crossword. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>412</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Diary</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a diary about StudyTopic. You are going to write a fictional diary about your experiences with StudyTopic. You should have 3 entries and include your feelings in relation to StudyTopic. Include 4 things you think are positive and 3 things that you think are negative [20 mins]. Share diary entries [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>413</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Keywords Story</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a story abmut StudyTopic using the StudyTopic keywords. We are going to write a story. First we&apos;ll write down 10 words related to StudyTopic. I am looking for 10 different students to each give me a different word [2 mins]. Groups of 3. You are eoing to turn these words into a story. You can put the words into any order you want. You must use all 10 words and you must have 10 sentences. You do not have to write anything down, but it will help you to make notes . You have 10 minutes, at the end of 10 minutes your group will tell your story to the class [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>414</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Movie Script</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a StudyTopic movie script. Your task is to write a StudyTopic scene for a movie script (in script format). Your script must have the dialogue of 3 people, no more and no less. At all times your script must be clear about who is speaking and what action is happening. Your movie scene must include at least 8 different StudyTopic words. You should describe all the important elements for the scene; props, location, lighting, weather, etc. [15 mins]. Groups of 3. Choose one of your scripts and rehearse [10 mins]. Groups act out scenes [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>415</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Newspaper Article</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a newspaper article about StudyTopic. Your task is to produce an interesting front page newspaper story about the dangers of StudyTopic. You need to have: a sensational headline, a catchy introductory paragraph, a totally made up middle paragraph and a frightening finishing paragpaph. We will judge the best ones and put them up on the display board [20 mins]. Time to judge the best ones. You are going to be the judges. You each have one sticky note. Choose which piece you think is the best and write on your sticky note why, then stick it onto the work [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>416</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Obituary</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an obituary to StudyTopic. What are all of the qualities of StudyTopic? Make a list of the good and bad qualities [5 mins]. Imagine that StudyTopic has died, your task is to write an obituary of StudyTopic. You need to sum up what it has done. Why was it important? How did it affect peoples lives? [15 mins]</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>417</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Television Show</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a television show about StudyTopic. What television shows are there about StudyTopic? Design your own 15 minute informative StudyTopic television show. How would the show start? What would be happening in the introductory video? What would the narrator say? What video clips would there be? How would you make the clips captivating? Would they be zoomed in, or taken from an unusual angle? For every two minutes draw a sketch representing what the video clip shows and write out what the commentary will be [20 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>418</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: What If Poetry</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a &apos;What if&apos; poem about StudyTopic. Your task is to make a poem with the title: &apos;What if StudyTopic...&apos; Each verse must have 5 lines and the first line for the first 3 verses are: What if StudyTopic had families? What if StudyTopic had rights? What if StudyTopic had colors? [10 minutes. Extension: Add a 4th verse with your own What if StudyTopic.....]. When we perform the poems think about the rhythm you use and how you use pauses for greater effect [Select learners randomly to read their poem. 10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>419</ID>
<Section>Activity</Section>
<Title>Write: Word Search</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a StudyTopic word search. These are 8 StudyTopic words that we are going to be using in today&apos;s lesson. Your first task is to think up a clue for each word. For instance if the word was coal you might say: 4 letters. It is black, found in the ground and burnt as fuel. You need to think up a clue for each of the 8 StudyTopic words [10 mins]. Your second task is to draw a 12x12 grid and add the 8 words. Then add letters around your words [10 mins]. In pairs swap your word searches and see if you can find the words [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>420</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Plenary</Title>
<Details>Groups of 2. You have 15 minutes to finish and review our StudyTopic lesson. Your task is to </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>421</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Not Appropriate</Title>
<Details>A plenary activity is not appropriate to the structure of this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>422</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Act Out: Charades</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to act out aspects of StudyTopic. On 6 small pieces of paper, each person is going to write down 6 different ideas about StudyTopic (keywords, concepts or ideas) [3 mins]. We will put all of our ideas into the plastic bag. Each group now comes and takes one piece of paper. Groups of 2. In your groups you mime (no talking allowed) the key learning/ ideas/ concepts whilst the other person guesses what it is. Then swap over and get a new piece of paper with a different StudyTopic word [10 mins]. Questions: Why did you do it in that way? How would other members in the group have done it differently?</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>423</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Agree: Targets</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to agree learning targets. Groups of 2 (high ability with low ability). Ask your partner the following questions: What three things have you learnt today? What would you like to find out more about? What does your neighbor think about StudyTopic? See if you can build consensus (agreement) with what you both think [5 mins]. Look through your partner’s work and set them 2 targets. The targets you set must be achievable and beneficial. Agree the targets with your partner and write them on their work [3 mins]. Join together with another group. Explain what you have discussed and the target you have been set [2 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>424</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Answer: Hot Seating</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer StudyTopic questions in the voice of different characters. You (or me the teacher) are going to take the &apos;hot-seat&apos; and answer questions in the role that the class have come up with. Those in the hot seat can choose their position, such as: Head of Research, Representative of a Group Affected By StudyTopic, Minister of StudyTopic or Member of The Public. The StudyTopic expert answers questions as knowledgeably (and nonchalantly) as they can. Change the person in the hot seat 4 times [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>425</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Anqwer: Quick-Fire</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer a set of quick-fire questions about StudyTopic. Think about what you have learnt about StudyTopic. Your task is to write 2 questions which you can now answer about StudyTopic. Once you are done put your questions into the box [2 mins]. I will read out a question from the box. Then I will say a name and it is that person&apos;s job to try and start answering that question within 3 seconds [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>426</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Answer: True Or False</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer true and false questions about StudyTopic. Is it True or is it False! I am going to ask you 5 StudyTopic questions about what we have already covered [4 mins]. Your task is to come up with 3 of your own questions. To do this look back through your StudyTopic notes [4 mins]. Now get into groups of 3 and share your questions [4 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>427</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Answers: Football</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to correctly answer questions about StudyTopic. This is a fun and interactive activity. Class in 2 teams. I am going to draw up a pitch with 5 lines running across it for marking goals. I will put the &apos;ball&apos; in the middle. You can either work as a team to answer questions or you can pick some out individually from each team. If you get a question right then you get tm move a line across and if they get 3 in a row you get to shoot. To save the other team has to answer their question right [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>428</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Articulate: Hot Seat</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to articulate StudyTopic words. Class in 2 teams. I need one member from each team to sit in front of the board. I am going to write a StudyTopic word on the board just above your heads (so you can&apos;t see it). When I say go your teams are going to help you guess the word (without saying it). Raise your hand when you think you know what the word is. The first team to guess it correctly wins a point x5 [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>429</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Assess: Classwork</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to assess StudyTopic work and identify useful deedback for improvements. Groups of 2. The first thing I want ymu to do is swap the StudyTopic work that you have done today [30 secs]. Your job is to carefully read through your partners work and then write down three pieces of feedback. Your feedback will say how the StudyTopic work could be improved. Your feedback needs to: Use full sentences. Be complimentary. Be helpful [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>430</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Assess: Learning Method</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to assess the method by which you learnt about StudyTopic. Visual, Auditory, Kinesthetic. What did we do today that was Visual? Auditory? Kinesthetic? How could you express what we did visually in an oral way? Can you express it Kinesthetically? Now let&apos;s think about what we learnt aurally.... [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>431</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Assess: Role Within Lesson</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to assess how you can improve your role within the lesson. Personal Learning and Thinking Skills. &apos;Look at these roles: Team Worker, Effective Participator, Creative Thinker, Self Manager, Reflective Learner, Independent Enquirer. Thinking about today&apos;s StudyTopic lesson explain: How did you use each of the skills? Choose one skill, how could you have improved it today? How will you aim to improve it next time? [5 mins] Repeat for each of the skills [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>432</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Brainstorm: What You Know?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to brainstorm what you now know about StudyTopic. Brainstorm everything you now know about StudyTopic [5 mins]. We are eoing to do a second brainstorm and this time we are going to use pictures instead of words [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>433</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Classify: Sentences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to classify different StudyTopic sentences. I want to invite you to look at the 3 StudyTopic texts. For each decide if they are: Fact/Opinion, Masculine/Feminine, Analytical/Emotional and Academic/Populist [10 mins]. Your challenge is to come up with you own classification systems (and a rationale behind it) [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>434</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Complete: Sentence Stems</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to complete a sentence about StudyTopic. In this hat are sentence stems about StudyTopic. {Sentence stems: StudyTopic is useful because..... If I were to learn something new about StudyTopic it would be .... What I most like about StudyTopic is ........ The thing that is most difficult about StudyTopic is....... The thing that it&apos;s most important to remember about StudyTopic is .........] If you have the hat when the music stops then you take a piece of paper and complete the sentence (or if it&apos;s too difficult choose someone else to complete it). Play music as the hat is passed around the room [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>435</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Complete: The Sentences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to complete sentences about StudyTopic. I am eoing to spin a bottle in the center of the class. The person that the bottle points to completes one of the following sentences: &apos;I would like to tell you about StudyTopic... I would like to explain why StudyTopic... Today I have learnt... One important thing to remember about StudyTopic is... The key focus today was... and this means... The best bit of StudyTopic is... because...&apos; [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>436</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Compose: A Poem</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to compose a poem about StudyTopic. Write a poem, 5 lines long and that rhymes, summing up what you have learnt today: This is a poem for plenary, About StudyTopic......, etc. [5 mins]. Read poems as a class [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>437</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Consider: 8 Perspectives</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to consider StudyTopic from 8 different perspectives. Groups of 2. On this plain sheet of paper draw a grid with 8 squares [1 min]. In each square answer one of the following questions. Numbers: How many types of StudyTopic are there? Words: Where does the word StudyTopic come from? People: Who discovered StudyTopic? Feelings: What emotions does StudyTopic have? Nature: How does StudyTopic affect the environment? Actions: What are all the things people do with StudyTmpic? Sounds: What songs (or noises) have been influenced by StudyTopic? Sights: What images represent StudyTopic? [15 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>438</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Create: Memory Aide</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to create your own StudyTopic memory aide. Your task is to come up with a way to remember StudyTopic. Your choices are; a mnemonic, a visual aid, a story or a song. In 15 minutes we will share our work [15 mins]. Now lay out your work on the table. Walk around the room and make a note of what you think are the 3 most helpful ways of remembering StudyTopic [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>439</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Define: 5 Words</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to define 5 StudyTopic words. Your task is to choose three new words you have learnt while studying StudyTopic and write diationary definitions for each of them [5 mins]. For each word write a paragraph explaining why it&apos;s important [10 mins]. Extension: Write a paragraph using all three words and explain how they are connected to StudyTopic [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>440</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Definitions: Who Wants To Be?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to correctly define StudyTopic words. Your task is to correctly define all of the StudyTopic definitions and win StudyTopic Millionaire. Class in 2 groups. This is a competition to see which team will be the StudyTopic knowledge kings. One student comes to the front, if they get a question correct the next student on the team gets to answer. Otherwise it goes to the other team. Rules: 1x take away two answers, 1x ask a friend, 1x ask the audience [10 mins]. Web search: &apos;Who Wants To Be A Millionaire StudyTopic template&apos;</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>441</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Deliver: News Report</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to deliver a News Report summarizing StudyTopic. Groups of 2. You have 10 minutes to prepare a 60 second news bulletin. One of you will be a news presenter and one of you will be a news reporter. Your news bulletin will either be about StudyTopic scenario 1 or StudyTopic scenario 2. To help your imagination have a look at these pictures for each of the scenarios. In 10 minutes we will look at your StudyTopic News Report [10 mins]. Students present [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>442</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Deliver: Poor Presentation</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to deliver a poor presentation about StudyTopic. Write down 5 sentences about StudyTopic, include all of the key points about StudyTopic [5 mins]. Groups of 2 (A, B). &apos;A&apos;s, take a Presentation Card and present your 5 sentences in the way your card describes [Presentation Cards: Rushing. Avoiding Eye Contact. Talking Quickly. Staring At The Ceiling. Bored. Excited. Smiling Constantly. Frowning. Talking Passionately. Wriggling. Pausing A Lot. Saying &apos;Erm&apos; A Lot. Quietly. Loudly. Jumping Up And Down. Your Back To Your Partner]. &apos;B&apos;s, your job is to guess how the sentences were delivered. &apos;A&apos;s and &apos;B&apos;s swap over, take a new card and repeat x3 [5 mins]. Swap partners and repeat with 3 more cards [5 mins]. [Deliberately acting in ways that are undesirable allows students to become aware of desirable and undesirable presentation behaviors. Focusing on delivery allows StudyTopic to be implicitly absorbed]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>443</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Describe: Taboo</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to describe StudyTopic words without using closely related words. On 2 separate scraps of paper write down 2 StudyTopic words from today&apos;s lesson, for each word write down 3 (taboo) commonly associated words. Place the pieces into this bag [3 mins]. Gpoups of 2. Take a word from the bag, your task is to describe the word without using it (it is taboo!). Swap over and repeat x5 [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>444</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Design: A Starter</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design a StudyTopic teaching starter activity. Your task is to design a StudyTopic teaching starter activity to use next lesson. Your starter needs to last for 1 minute. It could be a 5 questions quiz, a 2 tasks drawing activity, a crossword or something else. Your starter must review the 3 key points about StudyTopic [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>445</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Design: A Summary</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design a StudyTopic teaching plenary activity. I am inviting you to design an activity to summarize StudyTopic. You will carry out the activity at the start of next lesson. Your activity needs to: Last between 2 to 3 minutes. Include all of the StudyTopic Keywords. Be carried out by 4 other students. By the end of this lesson you need to have a clearly written plan of what you will do. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>446</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Design: Poster Adverts</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design a poster advert about StudyTopic. Using what you have learnt you are going to design a poster to advertise StudyTopic. Your challenge is to use no more than 7 words, that is your maximum word limit. Secondly your StudyTopic poster should be appropriate for your audiences, which is students 2 years younger than you [15 mins]. Review posters [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>447</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Design: Teaching Activity</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to design a teaching activity. Who has a younger sibling? Have you ever had to explain something they just didn&apos;t understand? Your task is to design a teaching activity for a student that is 3 years younger than you. You need to teach them all about StudyTopic, you have 5 minutes [5 mins]. You have 4 minutes to team up with one other person and try out their activity plus try out your activity [4 mins]. You are now going to be teaching students that are 5 years younger than you. What would be the strengths and weaknesses of your activity? [3 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>448</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discover: Word On My Back</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discover what StudyTopic word you have got on your back. [Stick StudyTopic keywords to the back of students] On your back is a word that we have studied today. Your task it find out what that word is. You are only allowed to ask each person in the room one Yes/No question and (for extra challenge) you are not allowed to use any of the StudyTopic keywords [5 mins]. Repeat changing words [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>449</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Conflict</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss different interpretations of StudyTopic and tensions that those can lead to. Where has conflict or tension arisen in today&apos;s lesson? There was tension between different interpretations of StudyTopic, why it that we think differently? Let&apos;s explore that in a discussion (relationships, learning) [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>450</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Controversial Issue</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss a controversial aspect of StudyTopic. Groups of 4. Look at this (controversial StudyTopic) statement: Why do we even bother with StudyTopic? In 10 minutes I&apos;m going to choose one person from your group. It will be that person&apos;s job to summarize the groups thoughts on the statement in 30 seconds [10 mins] Randomly chosen students summarize the groups thoughts [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>451</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Differences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss the different things learnt about StudyTopic. What is the most important idea that was generated in today&apos;s discussion? Can you explain StudyTopic in a different way? Can you explain StudyTopic using different words? Can you draw a diagram to illustrate StudyTopic? What do you think would improve the StudyTopic diagram? What bits are missing? What do you think is incorrect about the diagram? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>452</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Feelings And Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss feelings and questions about StudyTopic. Make a circle with your chairs. I want to use this next 10 minutes to Review, Reflect and Explore StudyTopic. I am going to throw this ball and if you have the ball you can choose to share what you are thinking or you can pass it to someone else. Discussion: Review - What have we learnt about StudyTopic? [3 mins] Reflect - What are our feelings about StudyTopic? [3 mins] Explore - What questions have you got about StudyTopic? [3 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>453</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Reflect, Recall, Evaluate</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to recall, reflect and evaluate our learning about StudyTopic. You are going to use your 3 sticky notes to share reflection, recall and evaluation about the StudyTopic lesson. Groups of 4. Each person in your group must complete 3 sticky notes. You can use either writing or pictures. When you have finished put your sticky notes onto the A3 sugar paper [5 mins]. Discuss as a group your feelings and thoughts about StudyTopic [5 mins].  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>454</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: What If?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss &apos;What If&apos; questions about StudyTopic. Discuss: What if we hadn&apos;t done today&apos;s lesson? What if you weren&apos;t allowed to know about StudyTopic? What if everything I&apos;ve told you today was false? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>455</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: What? How?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss what you learnt about StudyTopic and how you learnt it. Write down 3 things that you have learnt about StudyTopic. For each of those explain how you have learnt it [5 mins]. Discussion: What did you learn? How did you learn it? Why did you do it that way? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>456</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Discuss: Which Pic?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to discuss which skills you used when you learnt about StudyTopic. Look at the 6 pictures on the board [pictures of: new ideas, problem solving, discussion, experimenting, team/group work, creativity]. Groups of 2. Discussion: Which of these reflects what you have learnt about StudyTopic and why? [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>457</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: A Brainstorm</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to carry out a brainstorm about StudyTopic. Make a brainstorm that shows what you have learnt about StudyTopic. Around the core word StudyTopic you need to write 5 outer core words. Eaah of those then need to have 5 words around them [10 mins]. You now have 3 minutes to walk around and have look at the work that everyone else has done. As you walk around thilk of some words that you could add to your brainstorm. When I clap 3 times come back to your work and add those words [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>458</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: A Comic Strip</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a comic strip about StudyTopia. Your task is to produce a comic strip showing what you have learnt about StudyTopic. In your cartoon strip you must include at least 2 of these StudyTopic speech bubbles (e.g., Wow! StudyTopic really has the power to change the world.) [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>459</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: A Mind Map</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a mind map of StudyTopic. Closely look at this mind map and think about how it is structured. You can see that it summarizes all of the different parts of StudyTopic [2 mins]. Your task is to produce your own StudyTopic mind map. Your mind map needs to include all of the different StudyTopic words from this lesson. It must also summarize the important StudyTopic concepts. Think about hmw you can use different colors, icon and pictures to make your mind map more memorable [10 mins]. Hold up and show 3 exemplary mind maps emphasizing the important points of StudyTopic that have been captured [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>460</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: Concept Map</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a concept map about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Here are 15 words that are related to StudyTopic. Your task is to turn these into a concept map. Each word needs to be connected to at least one other word. For each connection that you make, you need to be able to justify why you have made that connection. In 10 minutes I&apos;m going to give you a word and I&apos;m going to ask you to stand up and justify the words you have connected it to [10 mins]. I am going to choose someone to justify their concept map x4 [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>461</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: Flow-Chart</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a flow chart to visually illustrate StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Draw a flow-chart showing the lesson and all of the parts that we have covered about StudyTopic. Think about how you can use shapes, diagrams and color to capture a visual impression of StudyTopic [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>462</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: Key Features</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a poster of the key features of StudyTopic. Your task is to create a poster about StudyTopic. The title for your StudyTopic poster will be: &apos;StudyTopic Key Features.&apos; Your poster must explain 5 key features and have a picture for each, showing each feature in action [10 mins]. Once you have finished you can label your pictures and add color to them [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>463</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: Shape And Color</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw the shape and color of StudyTopia. Use only shape and color to create an image of StudyTopic [5 mins]. Show your image to a partner and see if they can guess what the learning is [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>464</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Draw: The Learning</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw what you have learnt about StudyTopic. Draw the most important thing you have learnt today [5 mins]. Stand in 2 lines facing each other and explain your drawing [2 mins]. One line then moves along and the &apos;pairings&apos; change, repeat x3 [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>465</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Encode: rorriM</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to encode a message about StudyTopic using mirror writing. Mirror rorriM - Write one sentence that summarizes what you have learnt about StudyTopic. The challenge is to write it sdrawkcab (backwards) and reversed, so that if you held it up to a mirror you would be able to read it [5 mins]. Move around the room and swap your work with 3 different students. You decode their work and they decode your work [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>466</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Evaluate: Accomplishments</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to evaluate what we have accomplished in learning about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. In 10 minutes time I&apos;m going tm ask you to stand up and read out Four Things. Your task is to write down your answers to the following: What did we learn about StudyTopic? Did we meet our objectives? What are we not sure of? What did we miss out? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>467</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Evaluate: Three Things...</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to evaluate 3 things you have learnt. Tell Me Three Things: - You have learnt about StudyTopic. - You have done well. - The group has done well. - You would like to find out about StudyTopic - You now know about StudyTopic, that you didn&apos;t know at the start of the lesson. [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>468</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Evaluate: Unanswered Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to evaluate (as a group) what have learnt about StudyTopic and what questions we have that are unanswered. Today we have been studying: StudyTopic. On a piece of paper write down 3 questions to ask other people in the class about today&apos;s lesson [3 mins]. Ask 3 different people your questions and see if you can find out the answer to aly of them. If you find out the answer then write it down [2 mins]. There are some good questions here so I am going to collect them in and choose some to have a look at in another lesson [1 min].   </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>469</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Evaluate: WWW EBI</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to evaluate your StudyTopic learning. What Went Well and Even Better If. Think about our StudyTopic lesson. Your task is to write down 2 things that went well and one thing that would have improved the lesson [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>470</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Evaluation: Tree</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to evaluate StudyTopic using the structure of a tree. Groups of 5. In a moment I will give you an A3 piece of paper with a tree drawn on it [hold up paper]. Your task is to write the 10 StudyTopic words onto the tree. If you think that the word is core to StudyTopic then you write the word near the trunk. If you think it is a peripheral idea then you write it near to the leaves. In 10 minutes I will ask you to stand up and explain why your group has positioned the words where they are [10 mins]. Where have you put the StudyTopic words X and Z, why do you think they should go there? Let’s look at 2 different groups’ work: Group 1, can you answer first. Now group 2 [2 mins]. Each person in your group write your name onto your sheet of paper and next to your name write what it would take for you to feel even more comfortable with StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>471</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Explain: Mr. Wrong</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to explain why a sentenae about StudyTopic is wrong. The very best way to power a car is using StudyTopic! StudyTopic is as valuable as all of the worlds gold! Explain why these sentences are wrong [2 mins]. Look as these 3 (common StudyTopic misconceptions) sentences. Explain why each of these are wrong [3 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>472</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Explain: The Statement</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to explain the meaning of a StudyTopic statement. Groups of 3. In your groups take a number, 1, 2 or 3 [1 min]. On the board are 3 StudyTopic statements (numbered 1, 2 and 3) on the board. Look at your statement on the board, your task is to explain to the rest of the group what your statement means [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>473</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Fill-in: Missing Piece</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to fill-in the missing pieces of the StudyTopic process. Groups of 2. In the envelope in front of you is a StudyTopic process (or the lesson itself). It has been cut up. Your task is to put it into the right sequence. However, one (or more) of the bits is missing. You need to work out what should go in the place of the missing piece(s) [10 mins]. Write an explanation of the 5 parts of the StudyTopic process, explaining how each of the parts are connected. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>474</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Graph: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to draw a graph of StudyTopic. Think of the 3 different aspects of StudyTopic. For each of those aspects draw a graph that shows your learning. On the x axis show the time in the lesson and the y axis show you confidence with StudyTopic. For each of your graphs: Use a ruler, Add a title, Label the axes, Write an explanation of why you have drawn the graph the way it is [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>475</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Help: Tips</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to help someone studying about StudyTopic by writing them 5 helpful tips. Groups of 2. Your task is to write 5 helpful top tips about studying StudyTopic. In 10 minutes time we will put your work around the classroom and look at it. We will also decide on the best ones, which I will then use with next year’s class [10 mins]. Which do you think is the best one? You are going to use a sticky note to vote for the one you think is the best. On the sticky note write you name and why you think the one you have chosen is the best, then stick it onto the work [3 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>476</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Identify: Good, Bad, Ugly</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify the good, bad and ugly ways of answering StudyTopic questions. [Randomly choose 3 students to sit at the front of the class and give each student one card which says either Good, Bad or Ugly] You are an advice panel. I am going to pick students from the class to present a StudyTopic problem or question for you. You have to have to give an answer to that question which is either Good, Bad or Ugly (very bad) [Model a question and answers]. Pick a student to present a queqtion. Each panel member answers, then the student says which answer is good, which is bad and which is ugly. Repeat with 3 more questions from different students. Change the panel and repeat with new questions [15 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>477</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Identify: Hangman</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify and correctly spell StudyTopic words. Looking back over your notes about StudyTopic from today I&apos;d like you to find a word that you could use for haneman. Once you have found a word make sure that you know the definition of it [2 mins]. Class in 2 teams. I am going to choose one person to write up the spaces for their word and lead a game of hangman. Each team will take turns to choose a letter or guess the word. When the word has been guessed you will give the definition of the wmrd [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>478</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Imagine: Points Of View</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to imagine StudyTopic from different points of view. Imagine the different points of view people might have about StudyTopic. What would each of these people think: A Newspaper Editor, Your Neighbor, Your Dad, An Environmental Group, A Pensioner. For each write a sentence which summarizes their view [10 mins]. Extension: Add greater detail to you sentences, think about how that person feels towards StudyTopic and express their opinions. Add an additional sentence. Extension 2: Are there different types of people? Might different Environmental Groups hold different opinions?</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>479</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Improve: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to identify improvements to be made to StudyTopic. Your task is to identify some improvements that could be made to StudyTopic. Think about: How can StudyTopic be improved? Why would your changes be an improvement? Who for? How long would they last? [10 mins]. Think about not just the areas that we covered in detail in the lesson but also about the other areas of StudyTopic [3 mins]. I’ll pick 2 people to share their ideas [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>480</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Label: Diagram</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to label a diagram about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Look at this StudyTopic diagram/ picture/ illustration [2 mins]. Your task is to label ALL of the parts of StudyTopic and next to each part write an explanation of how it works [8 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>481</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Lini: Everyday Uses</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to link StudyTopic to everyday uses. How can you link today&apos;s lesson to your everyday life? Inside and outside of school, how can you use what you have learnt about StudyTopic? For each think of 3 contexts in which you might encounter StudyTopic, explain how what you have learnt will be useful [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>482</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Link: To StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make links between StudyTopic and 3 other subjects. Write down the names of three other subjects. For each of those subjects I would like you to answer the following questions. What links StudyTopic to the subject? How might StudyTopic affect that subject? How might you use StudyTopic in the subject? In what different ways might you encounter StudyTopic in the subject? What skills and knowledge might you take from StudyTopic and use elsewhere in your life? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>483</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Mark: Assessment</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a mark scheme and then assess your StudyTopic work. By actively taking part in the process of StudyTopic assessment you will gain a deeper understanding; of StudyTopic, of the process of assessment and of what they are doing in your own work. This will give you a greater awareness of &apos;what learning is&apos; and get you to start thinking about applying desired qualities to you own work. Groups of 2. Your task is to write out a mark scheme for the work that you have done. You need to have 4 criteria. For each criteria explain what you think a good piece of StudyTopic work looks like, what a satisfactory piece of StudyTopic work looks like and what a bad piece of StudyTopic work looks like [5 mins]. Your task is to self (or peer) - mark the class assessments using your student-made mark-scheme. For each of your criteria explain why you have given the mark you have. Then write 1 comment as to how you could improve the next piece of work you do [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>484</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Match Up: Dominoes</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to correctly match up questions and answers about StudyTopic. I am going to give you a large StudyTopic domino card. On your card is a StudyTopic question and an answer. Your task is to find the right people to join up your card. When you&apos;ve found the right person come and stand at the front of the room [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>485</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Match: Answer To Question</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to match the StudyTopic answers to the correct questions. I am going to give you either a question or an answer card, you can work out which one you have got. Your task is to match yourselves up in silence [5 mins]. Collect in the cards. We are now going to do the same thing but this time with a new card (this set has more answers than questions) [5 mins]. Collect in cards. Repeating with the first set of questions. This time we are going to stick the questions and answers onto your backs. You are only allowed to ask yes/ no questions. Match yourselves up [5 mins]. Collect the cards in. This time questions need to find questions that lead to the same answer and answers find answers that could be from the same question [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>486</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Meaning: My Word!</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to give the meaning of the StudyTopic words we have used today. Choose one StudyTopic word that has been used during the lesson [1 min]. (Choose a student to stand up) it is your job to say your word and then and point to someone in the class who will give the meaning. That person then chooses the next person to answer the meaning of a new word. Repeat x 10 [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>487</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Perform: Professor v Ignoramus</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to perform a dialogue in character about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Your task is to create a 60 second dialogue between a StudyTopic Professor and StudyTopic Ignoramus. You don&apos;t have to write anything but you may find it useful if you do? You have 10 minutes to prepare [10 mins]. I&apos;ll now randomly choose 2 groups to perform their dialogues [5 mins]. Discuss misconceptions about StudyTopic [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>488</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Position: Continuum</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to position yourself in terms of your opinion about StudyTopic. This is particularly useful for helping you to make an informed judgments. We are going to use a continuum so that you can identify yourself with a position or stance related to StudyTopic. This is the continuum going all the way across the classroom. On one end &apos;StudyTopic is good&apos; on the other &apos;StudyTopic is bad&apos;, go and stand where you feel is right. I am going to ask you to say why you have put yourself where you are  on the continuum; you are only allow to give reasons based on evidence from the lesson [5 mins]. Get into groups of 4. Decide on a continuum question or statement that we could pose to the class [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>489</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Predict: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make 3 predictions based on what you now know about StudyTopic. I want you to make 3 predictions based on the knowledge you have gained about StudyTopic: We are carrying on with StudyTopic what do you think we will study next lesson? How would the world be different if StudyTopic were more important than it is now? What changes would happen if StudyTopic stopped working? [5 mins]. Share suggestions as a class [4 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>490</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Present: Voice Over</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to present a voice over to a video clip about StudyTopic. Groups of 4. 2 students sit facing each other and have a silent conversation, moving their mouths whilst the other two stand behind and provide the voice-over. Have the beginnings of a conversation about the lesson on the board to start them off. Sitters sound the alarm if speakers go &apos;off-topic&apos; or fail to synchronize their speech with the sitter&apos;s mouth movements [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>491</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Prioritize: 5, 5, 1</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to prioritize ideas about StudyTopic. Your first task is to summarize the StudyTopic lesson in 5 sentences. Once you have finished your 5 sentences go and stand next to someone who is still writing and help them to finish [5 mins]. Go back to your seats. Your second task is to reduce your 5 sentences to the 5 most important StudyTopic words. When you have written down your words discuss with the person next to you why you have chosen those 5 words [3 mins]. Your final task is to summarize your 5 words to a single word. When you have chosen your word, explain to the person next to you why you have chosen it [3 mins]. Extension: Repeat, this time using shapes and pictures [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>492</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Produce: Freeze Frame</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to produce a freeze frame depicting StudyTopic. Groups of 3. A freeze-frame is when everything and everyone are still, but the essence of the idea of the idea is captured in your positions and expressions. Your task is to capture the essence of the 3 different things we have learnt about StudyTopic. The more dramatic you can make it the better. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>493</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Provide: A Forecast</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to provide a forecast about StudyTopic in the future. Groups of 2. In 5 minutes time I am going to seleat one person in you pair. Your task is to provide your forecast and reasoning for the following two situations: If what you have learnt about StudyTopic is true, what will the future be like? If what you have learnt about StudyTopic were false, what would the future be like? [5 mins] </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>494</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Qualities: Acrostic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize the qualities of StudyTopic in an acrostic. This activity will get you thinking really deeply about the qualities of StudyTopic. What is an acrostic? [1 min]. For each letter of StudyTopic you are going to think of a quality. Write StudyTopic vertically down your page and for each letter write one quality starting with that letter. If you can&apos;t think of one you can cheat and use 2 or 3 words [3 mins]. See if you can come up with a second totally different acrostic [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>495</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Question: Ball</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to throw a ball and ask and answer questions about StudyTopic. I am going to ask a question and then throw the ball. If you catch the ball you need to answer the question and ask a related follow-up question. You then throw the ball to someone else who answers your question. Let&apos;s begin, the first question is: &apos;What is StudyTopic?&apos; Let&apos;s see who is going to answer it (throw the ball). We&apos;ll continue until someone is unable to think of an answer, a question, or an on-topic response to a question [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>496</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Question: Group Quiz</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer questions about StudyTopic. Groups of 4. In 10 minutes you are going to be quizzed about StudyTopic by the rest of the class. You could be asked about anything at all so get ready [10 mins]. One group come to the front and are quizzed by the rest of the class on what they have learnt, how they have learnt and what skills they have used/developed [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>497</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Question: Probing</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to ask probing questions about StudyTopic. Groups of 4. In your group select a quiz master. It is the quiz master&apos;s job to keep track of the scores of all of the group. For the quiz master there is a StudyTopic sheet with 10 questions and answers. After the quiz master asks the question everyone in the group must give their answer. The quiz master must also probe everyone for an explanation of why they have chosen their answer [model how this works]. After each question the quiz master reveals the correct answer the group, and notes down who was right. At the end announce the winner [5 mins]. Using what you have learnt about StudyTopic your task is to come up with your own StudyTopic Quiz. Your quiz should have 5 questions [5 mins]. Groups of 4, everyone carries out their quiz [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>498</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Question: Tennis</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to ask and answer questions about StudyTopic. Arrange the class in two team (in rows) facing each other. The first person asks the person opposite a question about StudyTopic. If they answer it correctly the person sat next to them gets to ask a question of the student opposite. If they get it wrong, the first team continue asking the questions. A1 asks B1. If B1 gets it right, then B2 asks A2. If B1 gets it wrong, then A2 asks B2, etc. [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>499</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Question: The Teacher</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to ask questions about StudyTopic. Your task is to try and beat the teacher! Come up with questions based around your learning today and see if the teacher can answer your StudyTopic questions. On two scraps of paper write down 2 questions and place them into the bag [4 mins]. One student is the quiz master and sits opposite the teacher at the front of the class and pulls out 2 questions to ask. They then select the next quiz master. Repeat x5 [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>500</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Questions: Remaining</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write down any questions you have remaining about StudyTopic. Write down 2 questions that you still have about StudyTopic [3 mins]. Walk around the room and ask 3 students your questions. If your question is answered then put it into the trash. Put any unanswered questions onto the desk (answer each of the unanswered questions - if an answer is possible) [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>501</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflect: Improvements, How?</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on how you could improve your knowledge and ability in StudyTopic. How do you feel about the lesson objectives for StudyTopic? Use colored pens to indicate on your work how you feel about what you have done. Red = I don&apos;t think I have grasped this. Amber = I am feeling OK about this and I have just about got there. Green = I am confident I have achieved this [2 mins]. Write on your work hmw you think you could have imprmved. What would you need to do to get yourself to green or to take yourself to the next level? [3 mins]</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>502</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflect: Interesting Learnt Struggled</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on our learning about StudyTopic. Write 3 paragraphs reflecting on StudyTopic. Each paragraph should start with the following: What I found interesting was.... What I learnt was....... What I struggled with was........[6 mins]. Share as a class [3 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>503</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflect: Know, Understand, Use</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on what I now know, understand and can use about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. In 5 minutes I am going to call out some StudyTopic names. Your assignment is to be ready to read your answers to the following questions: As a result of the lesson today I know _____ about StudyTopic. I understand _____ about StudyTopic. I can use information about StudyTopic in the following other situations _____. [5 mins]. Lets hear from .... x2 [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>504</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflect: Learning</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on what you have learnt about StudyTmpic. Write a reflection of how your thinking about StudyTopic has changed over time. Think about each of the different aspects of StudyTopic. Complete these 3 sentences for each of the aspects of StudyTopic. At first I thought .... Then I thought ..... Now I think ..... [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>505</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflect: Success!</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on our successes in learning about StudyTopic. In studying StudyTopic I have been successful in the following three ways... I could make this better next time if I... If I were starting again and designing this for myself I would do this instead... [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>506</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflection: Meta Learning Plenary</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on learning about StudyTopic. Groups of 2. With your partner discuss the following questions: How are you going to remember what you have learnt about StudyTopic? What key point will you remember about StudyTopic? What has StudyTopic reminded you of? Which senses were most important in learning about StudyTopic? What did you learn about StudyTopic that you didn’t know before? What have you learnt that could be useful elsewhere? What have you learnt elsewhere that is like StudyTopic? How will you apply what you have learnt about StudyTopic? [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>507</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Reflection: Sentence</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to reflect on the StudyTopic lesson. You have 30 seconds to think of one sentence that summarizes your thoughts about this StudyTopic lesson [30 secs]. I’ll throw this paper airplane whoever it lands near pick up the plane and share your sentence. Now throw the plane towards someone else x10 [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>508</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Sculpt: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to make a sculpture of StudyTopic. Using a random bag of packaging, newspapers, fabrics, materials, etc., your task is to make a sculpture of the lesson/ your learning/ or a key StudyTopic concept [20 mins]. Discuss which are the best sculptures and why, the best 2 are then displayed onto the classroom plinth/ shelf [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>509</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Set: Targets</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to set targets for how you will improve. Discuss: Exemplar StudyTopic work, Ideas of targets. What questions do you have? [5 mins]. Write down your answers to: What three things have you done well this lesson? What can you improve next lesson? How will you do this? [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>510</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Share: Next Lesson</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to share what you know about next week&apos;s lesson. Next lesson we are going to be studying _____ you have 2 minutes to ask your neighbor what they know and to also share what you know. In 2 minutes I will ask you to stand up and say what you have found out [2 mins]. What does your neighbor know about _____? I am going to choose someone at random to answer.... x5 [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>511</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Share: This Lesson</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to share what you have learnt this lesson. This lesson we have learnt about StudyTopic. You have 2 minutes to ask your neighbor what 2 words, 2 facts they have learnt. Finally what 2 questions do they now have? At the end of 2 minutes I will ask you what your neighbor has found out [2 mins]. I am going to choose a student at random to share what they found out... x5 [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>512</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Show: And Comment</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to show and then comment on the StudyTopic work. Groups of 2. Your task is to look at your partner&apos;s StudyTopic work and to give them comment on how they can improve. 2 stars for things your think are good and a wish for something you think could be improved. Groups join together to form groups of 4. Your task is to share your partners StudyTopic work along with your feedback [8 mins]. For students who have done exemplar StudyTopic work/would benefit from public praise or encouragement share their work with the whole class [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>513</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Speak: Chinese Whispers</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to speak clearly and accurately about StudyTopic. On a scrap of paper write down one sentence that summarizes your learning. Once you have written your sentence bring it to the desk at the front of the class. Arrange yourselves into lines of 6. The person at the end of the line comes and gets one of the sentences. The objective is to whisper the sentence from the end of the line to the front. [for each of the lines] What have we got at the front of the line? What did we have at the start? [change the line order and repeat 2 more times]. With your partner what do you think this tells you about communication, memory and listening? [2 minute discussion]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>514</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Speak: Frame</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to speak about StudyTopic using sentence stems to focus our thinking. Groups of 2. Your task is to complete the following sentences: Today we tried to find out why StudyTopic .... We discovered that StudyTopic.... What we enjoyed the most was about StudyTopic was....[5 mins]. I&apos;ll choose some groups to present their answers, first is... x3 [4 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>515</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Speak: Just A Minute</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to speak clearly, concisely and confidently about StudyTopic. Groups of 4. Your challenge is to speak for 1 minute about StudyTopic. You are not allowed to: Hesitate (Pause or say &apos;erm&apos;), Repeat or Make A Mistake. One of your group will start to speak about StudyTopic. At the first repetition, pause or mistake I will say NEXT and the next student takes over. We will carry on until the minute is up. You have 5 minutes now to prepare [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>516</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summarize: Animal Voice</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize your learning about StudyTopic in the voice of an animal. Summarize what you have learnt about StudyTopic in the character of an animal. Explain what StudyTopic means to your animal [10 mins]. You are going to share what you have learnt and the class are going to guess which animal you chose [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>517</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summarize: As A Celebrity</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize StudyTopic from the perspective of a celebrity. If Sean Connery were to summarize StudyTopic, what would he say? [give an example with an accent] Your task is to summarize StudyTopic in the voice of your favorite celebrity. You have 5 minutes to write out what you would say and practice. Then we&apos;ll perform for the class. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>518</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summarize: Headline</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize StudyTopic by writing a headline. Write 3 different newspaper headlines (sensational, serious, tabloid) about StudyTopic [3 mins]. Choose one of your headlines and make a plan of the article to go with the headline. What are the details that would be included [10 mins]? Add a picture to go with your headline [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>519</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summarize: Number Of Words</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize StudyTopic in X words. Pick a number between 5 and 15 and write that on your paper [10 seconds]. Your task is to summarize what you have learnt about StudyTopic in the number of words you have written down on your paper [3 mins]. Now we are going to share the summaries [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>520</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summary: Countdown Write</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to summarize StudyTopic within 1 or 2 minutes. On the board is a 1 minute countdown timer. Your challenge is to write a summary of the lesson in sixty-seconds. The timer starts now [1 min]. I am going to randomly choose 4 students to read out their summations to the class x4 [4 mins]. Repeat: This time you have 2 mins and you need to include these StudyTopic words/phrases [2 mins]. I am going to randomly choose 4 students to read out their summations to the class x4 [4 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>521</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summary: Equation</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an equation that summarizes StudyTopic. An equation is a condensed way of summarizing all of the important parts of a topic or idea. Your task is to write an equation showing the important parts of StudyTopic. For instance: (Gas + Flour + Milk + Sugar) x Oven = Cake. What would be the equation that summarizes StudyTopic? Be ready to justify why your answer is a complete answer [5 mins]. Discussion: What is your summary? [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>522</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Summary: Your Style</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a summary of StudyTopic in your own writing style. Your task is to write up what you have learnt about StudyTopic. You can either write a StudyTopic newspaper article,  a teenage magazine article or a blog interview article. Your article should have 600 words [20 mins]. Listen to 3 students read their articles [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>523</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Talk: One Minute One Question</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to talk about StudyTopic for one minute and then ask one question about what you have said. Your challenge is to talk for one minute about StudyTopic. At the end of that minute you will need to ask a challenging question to the class about what you have said. You have 10 minutes to prepare and practice (for extra challenge you should not bring any notes) [10 mins]. [randomly choose a student] You need to talk for 1 minute about StudyTopic and at the end ask a challenging question [student chooses who answers the question after they ask it]. Repeat x5 [7 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>524</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Teach: StudyTopic</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to teach about StudyTopic. Groups of 3. In 10 minutes time you are going to be the teacher. You will have one minute to as a group summarize StudyTopic and each of you will need to ask a StudyTopic question to the class [10 mins]. The first group to present and ask their question is.... x3 [6 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>525</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Word-Fill: Sentences</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to correctly fill in sentences with StudyTopic words. Fill in the missing words (can include the words underneath - in the wrong order of course - for differentiation) The X _____ is a popular program on _____ All of the contestants are extremely _____ and _____ . Simon Cowell always says _____ things and makes the performers feel _____ about themselves. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>526</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: A Complaint</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a complaint about StudyTopic. Write a complaint about &apos;The Three Dangers Of StudyTopic&apos;. If you could make StudyTopic less dangerous how would you do it? [15 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>527</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: A Problem</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to answer and then write your own StudyTopic problem. Your task is to solve this StudyTopic problem (problem from: lesson objectives, something signposted in the lesson or a general StudyTopic question). You will need to select the information and learning from the lesson that will enable you to solve the problem [5 mins]. Your second task is to come up with a StudyTopic problem which you will then ask others to solve [5 mins]. Share your problem with 3 different students [5 mins]. Extension: Write a review list of information from the lesson [5 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>528</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: A Recipe</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a recipe for how to make StudyTopic. What is a recipe? Could you write a recipe to make pizza? Your task is to write out a recipe to make pizza [3 mins]. Share with partners. Have your fully explained how to make your pizza? Could you have made a more detailed recipe? [1 min] Today we have learnt about StudyTopic. Your task is to write a comprehensive recipe to make StudyTopic [5 mins]. Share your StudyTopic recipe with the person next to you [3 mins]. Is it clear? Why, why not? What do you think could have been added? Did it miss out any of the &apos;ingredients&apos; of StudyTopic? What could have improved the StudyTopic recipe? [5 mins]. Make improvements or (if already perfect) add an illustration [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>529</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: A Tweet</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a tweet summarizing what you have learnt about StudyTopic. Write a tweet which summarizes what you have learnt in today&apos;s lesson. You can only use 140 characters [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>530</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Anagrams</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write an anagram about StudyTopic. Your task is to unravel the anagrams to reveal the (StudyTopic) key words /phrases /ideas from the lesson [5 mins]. Now you are going to come up with your own &apos;mana rags&apos; [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>531</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Brain Summary</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a summary of the knowledge your brain has acquired about StudyTopic. Projected on the board is an outline of a brain. Your task is to draw a copy in your book [3 mins]. Now your task is to write in everything you have learnt today (knowledge and skills) about StudyTopic [10 mins]. (Students could draw the brain at the start of the lesson so as to signpost that they will be able to fill it up by the end). </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>532</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Exam Questions</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write exam questions about StudyTopic. Write an exam questiol about StudyTopic. Then, swap books and answer someone else&apos;s question. Challenge students by writing a mark scheme for the question as well, using peer/self assessment or using different types of exam questions - multiple choice, short answer, essay, etc. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>533</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: From Different Shoes</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write about StudyTopic from different perspectives. For each of the following: Our Country&apos;s President/ A University Professor/ Steve Jobs. Had they taught today&apos;s lesson about StudyTopic, how might it have been different? Explain your answer. In six minutes we will have some students read their answers aloud [6 mins]. I am going to randomly pick a student to read aloud their answer x 4 [4 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>534</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: How, Where, When, Why,</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write down the How, Where, When and Why of StudyTopic. Groups of 2. Your task is to use full sentences to answer the following questions: How does StudyTopic work? Where does StudyTopic work? When does StudyTopic work? Why does StudyTopic work? How does StudyTopic affect people? Where does StudyTopic affect people? When does StudyTopic affect people? Why does StudyTopic affect people? [10 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>535</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Mnemonic Phrases</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a mnemonic phrase about StudyTopic. Looking at these 3 groups of (StudyTopic) words. Your task is to create 3 mnemonic phrases to remember them. For example... You have 10 minutes to come up with your own [10 mins]. We&apos;ll share our mnemonic phrases [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>536</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Pyramid</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to fill out a pyramid with what you have learnt about StudyTopic. Draw a pyramid and at the bottom write in 3 things you have learnt about StudyTopic. Beneath that write in two StudyTopic words that have made an impression on you. At the top write in one question you have about StudyTopic [5 mins]. Share your pyramid with the person next to you [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>537</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Storyboard</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a storyboard about StudyTopic. Make a storyboard about today&apos;s StudyTopic lesson. Your storyboard needs to show what you did and how you learnt. You also need to explain the key StudyTopic concepts that you learnt and why they are important [10 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>538</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Summary Song</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a summary song about StudyTopic. Choose a music style, sum up StudyTopic and then recite it in your chosen style: Write a rap about the lesson, Do a group monastic chant or Sing a country style song [10 mins]. Perform to the class [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>539</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Txt Msg</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write a text message summarizing your learning about StudyTopic. What&apos;s that sound? Oh look I have just received a text. Your task is using text speak write a &apos;3 txt msg&apos; explaining what you have learnt about StudyTopic. You must cover one of the keywords from StudyTopic. Remember you must use no more than 160 characters. You have 6 minutes before sending [6 mins]. I am going to randomly choose someone to read out their message, first up is.... x4 [4 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>540</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: World Change</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write down how StudyTopic could change the world. How could what you have learnt about StudyTopic change the world? Answer the following questions: On a local level? On a national level? On a global level? [5 mins]. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>541</ID>
<Section>Plenary</Section>
<Title>Write: Your Homework Task</Title>
<Details>Objective: To be able to write your own homework task. What homework would you set yourself on what you have learnt today? How would this help you to build on what you have learnt? [3 mins ]. As class can vote for the best StudyTopic homework [4 mins]. You have a choice, either do the homework you wrote down or do the homework we voted as the best one as a class. Write down your homework into your homework planner [2 mins].</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>542</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Homework</Title>
<Details>Your homework is to be handed in on this lesson next week. Your StudyTopic homework is to </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>543</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Previously Set</Title>
<Details>Homework has been set during previous lessons and will not be set for this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>544</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Blogging</Title>
<Details>Your task is to write a blog entry about StudyTopic and post it. You can use any blogging website you want. In your blog you need to include 4 of the keywords we have studied in StudyTopic. Next week we might not have access to a computer room so I would like you to print off your work. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>545</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Collage</Title>
<Details>Create a collage that represents the 4 most important aspects of StudyTopic. You should include a paragraph that describes what you have created and how it represents StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>546</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Description</Title>
<Details>Write a description of StudyTopic. What color is it? What does it smell like? What does it taste like? What does it sound like? What does it feel like? Where does it live? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>547</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Enhance</Title>
<Details>I would like you to enhance your work from the lesson. You will need to use greater detail in describing each of the StudyTopic keywords. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>548</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Film Script</Title>
<Details>Write a scene from a film script about StudyTopic. Choose your genre (comedy, sci-fi, romance) and write two pages with dialogue and scene descriptions.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>549</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Flyer</Title>
<Details>Design a flyer to sell the idea of StudyTopic. We will peer assess your work at the start of next lesson. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>550</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Game</Title>
<Details>Create your own game about StudyTopic. You must have questions cards and board spaces that are named after StudyTopic keywords. You should have 10 StudyTopic questions and answers.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>551</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Illustration </Title>
<Details>Produce an illustration showing an aspect of StudyTopic. Your illustration should include a paragraph describing what you&apos;ve drawn and why it&apos;s important to StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>552</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Instant Message</Title>
<Details>Have an Instant Message conversation about StudyTopic. Your conversation should be 1 page long. Print off your conversation and add it into your book. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>553</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Model</Title>
<Details>Create a 3D model that shows all the parts of StudyTopic. Put on labels explaining how the parts of StudyTopic work.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>554</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>News Story</Title>
<Details>Find a news story about StudyTopic. Print it off and highlight the keywords that we have studied in class. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>555</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Next Week - 3 Facts</Title>
<Details>In preparation for next weeks lesson find out 3 facts about the topic we will be doing next lesson. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>556</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Noting Page</Title>
<Details>Over the next week you are going to keep a noting page. Each day you are going to make an entry and note down what you have seen that day which is connected to StudyTopic. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>557</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Phone Photo</Title>
<Details>Your task is to use your mobile phones to bring in 3 pictures related to StudyTopic. If your phone doesn&apos;t have a camera you could bring in clippings from newspapers or magazines.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>558</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Quiz</Title>
<Details>Prepare a quiz about StudyTopic and try it out on 2 people from your family. Your quiz should have at least 5 questions and your should write down the correct answer as well as the first answer that the members of your family give you.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>559</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Record</Title>
<Details>Record yourself reading a page about StudyTopic from the unit textbook. Bring in the recording on your phone. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>560</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Sales Pitch</Title>
<Details>Choosing one of the two ideas covered in the lesson write a thirty-second sales pitch to sell the idea. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>561</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Song</Title>
<Details>Write a song about StudyTopic. You must have a chorus and two verses. You should try to include 5 of the keywords we have studied.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>562</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Survey</Title>
<Details>Create and then carry out a survey about StudyTopic. Your might like to carry out the survey with your parents/ guardians or your neighbors. Your StudyTopic survey should include 3 closed questions and 2 open questions. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>563</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Timeline</Title>
<Details>Produce a timeline that shows StudyTopic. You timeline must include: 5 key dates and at least 2 sentences for each date and 2 pictures illustrating events that took place during your timeline. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>564</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Transcribed Interview</Title>
<Details>Produce a timeline which shows the development and changes of StudyTopic over the course of 50 years.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>565</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Video Quiz</Title>
<Details>Groups of 2. Your task is to create a 5 question video quiz about StudyTopic. In between each question you will need to pause before you then give the answer and ask the next question. You will need to upload your videos to a video sharing website and we will watch a selection of them next lesson. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>566</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Vocabulapy Book</Title>
<Details>Over the next 5 weeks construct a vocabulary book of terms that we have used during the lesson. For each lesson you must have at least 2 words. For this lesson you must have 2 words about StudyTopic. Each word must take up a whole page and have; a detailed explanation, example and diagram or illustration. In 5 weeks time you will hand in your vocabulary book for assessment.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>567</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Watch A Video</Title>
<Details>Find a video about StudyTopic (it could be on the internet) and write down 2 things that you learnt about StudyTopic from watching the video.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>568</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Why Is It Best?</Title>
<Details>Your homework is to find your proudest piece of work. You then need to tell me why it is your best piece of work. Your explanation needs to have at least 3 different reasons (e.g., neatness, amount of time you spent, that it is original, the grade you received, or the amount you learnt). Add just one thing that you think you could improve if you were going to do it again. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>569</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Wiki Story</Title>
<Details>I have started a story at WikiWebAddress. Over the course of the next week I would like you to make a contribution to that story using any 3 words that we have covered so far in the unit. When you make your contribution you need to login so that I can see you have made a contribution. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>570</ID>
<Section>Homework</Section>
<Title>Word Play</Title>
<Details>Write an acrostic or crossword about StudyTopic. You must include 5 of the keywords that we have studied in StudyTopic. If you choose to produce a crossword you should make alues for each of your words.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>571</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Resources</Title>
<Details>The StudyTopic resources we will need are </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>572</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Classroom Resources</Title>
<Details>The classroom that resources that are required for this StudyTopic lesson are: Textbooks, Worksheets, Exercise Books, Dictionaries, Paper, Pens, Pencils, Whiteboard Markers, Mini Whiteboards, Classroom Computer, Interactive Whiteboard, DVD&apos;s, CD&apos;s, Website URL&apos;s. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>573</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Assessment</Title>
<Details>Labels, Mini Whiteboards, Whiteboard Markers, Mini Whiteboards Erasers, Traffic Light Cards (Green, Orange, Red), Laminated ABCD Cards, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>574</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Audio Visual</Title>
<Details>A class set of: Video Cameras, Digital Cameras, Memory Cards, Tapes, Batteries, Chargers, Connection Cables, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>575</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Books</Title>
<Details>Textbooks, Exercise Books, Dictionaries, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>576</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Classroom Computer</Title>
<Details>Computer, Interactive Whiteboard, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>577</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Collage Materials</Title>
<Details>Various Colored Paper, Magazines, Cardboard boxes, Materials, Cardboard, Glue, Scissors, Pencils, Glitter,  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>578</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Computers</Title>
<Details>A class set of: Computers, Printers, Scanners, Data Loggers, Headphones, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>579</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Creativity</Title>
<Details>Paints, Pens, Pencils, Erasers, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>580</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Designing Kit</Title>
<Details>Pencils, Drawing Boards, Isometric Paper, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>581</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Display Board Kit</Title>
<Details>Staplers, Display Stapler, Colored Backing Paper, Scissors, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>582</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Drawing</Title>
<Details>Compasses, Protractors, Rulers, Pencils, Colored Pens, Colored Pencils, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>583</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Graphing</Title>
<Details>Graph Paper, Squared Paper, Pencils, Protractors, Erasers, Compasses, tracing paper, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>584</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Included</Title>
<Details>All of the resources required for this lesson are included within the lesson plan.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>585</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Math</Title>
<Details>A class set of: Calculators, Graph Paper, Squared Papep, Scissors, tracing paper, timers, Data Loggers, Trundle Wheel, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>586</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Math Counting</Title>
<Details>A class set of: Calculators, Abacuses, Plastic Money, Talk Balls, Dice, Dominoes, Plastic Cubes, Arithmetic Racks, Multisided Dice, Spinners, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>587</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Math Equipment</Title>
<Details>A class set of: Large Dice, Paper Money, Coins, colored 3D shapes, graph paper, protractors, pens, giant dominoes, big number cards, large number grid, giant playing cards, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>588</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>None Required</Title>
<Details>There are no additional resources required for this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>589</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Outdoor Drawing</Title>
<Details>Large pieces of colored chalk, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>590</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Outdoor Measuring </Title>
<Details>Tape Measures, Stop Watches, Thermometers, Meter Rulers, Clinometers, Pedometers, Trundle Wheels, Compasses, Note Books, Clipboards, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>591</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Painting Kit</Title>
<Details>A4 and A3 colored paper, Paints, Pens, Pencils, Rubbers, Paint Pots, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>592</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Poster Kit</Title>
<Details>A4 Paper, A3 Paper, Envelopes, Sticky Notes, Scotch tape, Marker Pens, Colored Pens. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>593</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Reports Kit</Title>
<Details>Lined Paper, Plastic Sleeves, Folders, Labels, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>594</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Science Biology</Title>
<Details>Biology Laboratory - A class set of: Choice Chambers, Agar Plates, Quadrats, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>595</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Science Chemistry</Title>
<Details>Chemistry Laboratory - A class set of: Ethanol, Distilled Water, Conical Flasks, Test Tubes, Boiling Tubes, Bunsen Burners, Heat Proof Matts, Tripods, Gauzes, pH Indicator Paper, pH Indicator, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>596</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Science Physics</Title>
<Details>Physics Laboratory - Van de Graaff Generator, Power Boxes, Volt Meters, Ammeters, Meter Rulers, Torches, Prisms, Lasers, Light Boxes, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>597</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Stationery Paper</Title>
<Details>A4 Paper, A3 Paper, Lined Paper, Plain Paper, White Paper, Colored Paper, Tracing Paper, Isometric Paper, Graph Paper, Squared Paper, </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>598</ID>
<Section>Resources</Section>
<Title>Worksheets</Title>
<Details>A class set of StudyTopic Worksheets and the resources specified in the worksheets. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>599</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Reminder</Title>
<Details>During the StudyTopic lesson we must remember to </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>600</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Classroom Guidelines</Title>
<Details>Please leave the classroom tidy, neat and clean. Count out and in all resources that are used. Before the end of the lesson return all resources to where they where they were taken from. If any resources are damaged place them on the front desk. Do make a note of any students that are particularly well behaved so that I can follow up with them. If there are discipline issues follow the school behavior policy.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>601</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Absent Students</Title>
<Details>How am I making today&apos;s lesson available for absent students? What can I do to get absent students fully participating in the next lesson? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>602</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Accessibility</Title>
<Details>How could I use easy to understand terms to make StudyTopic concepts more accessible? What StudyTopic characters could I play and introduce? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>603</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Ask, Wait, Name</Title>
<Details>It can take 10-15 seconds to retrieve the information from our memories and think of a response. To get every single student to figure out the answer ask the StudyTopic question first and give 15 seconds wait time. Then and only then say the name of the student that is required to answer the question.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>604</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Attention Getter - Claaaass!</Title>
<Details>When I say &apos;Class&apos; you are going to say &apos;Yes&apos;. If I say &apos;Claaaas&apos; you say &apos;Yeeees&apos;, if I say &apos;Classity Claass&apos; you say? &apos;Yessity yees&apos;. Now let&apos;s practice. &apos;Class&apos; [class responds] we can do better &apos;Class!&apos; [wait for response] &apos;Classity Claass&apos; [wait for response]. Listen out for that because we&apos;ll be doing more of it throughout the lesson. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>605</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Attention Getter - Lights</Title>
<Details>To get everyone&apos;s attention at the end od a noisy task switch the lights off and on. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>606</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Attention Getter - Various</Title>
<Details>Hands Raised, Clapping with a rhythm that the class repeats, Bell, Shouting &apos;freeze&apos;, Finger in front of mouth.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>607</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Check In</Title>
<Details>Periodically check understanding with thumbs up /down. Yes/No, +/- cards, 1,2,3,4 fingers. &apos;Hold up 4 fingers if you think the answer is D.&apos; </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>608</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Cliffhanger</Title>
<Details>What cliffhanger will I include in this lesson to whet learners&apos; appetite for the next class: A queqtion, an interesting fact, a riddle, handout(s), a picture on the board or a brief discussion? Will I build suspense for the next lesson by leaving a question unanswered until the following class? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>609</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Co-operation</Title>
<Details>How am I conveying the expectation of student co-operation? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>610</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Collect Homework</Title>
<Details>Collect in the homework that was set last week.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>611</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Color Folders</Title>
<Details>Use color folders to organize and file class information, making it easier to find. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>612</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Count Out And In</Title>
<Details>We need two volunteers. You are the equipment monitors. It is your job to count up how many pieces of equipment (Scissors, Rulers, etc.) we have and make sure that everything is working. At the end of the lesson before we go I would like you to count in all the lesson equipment and to check that everything is working. I will do a final double check. Looking after our resources is important because we need to use them for the whole year. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>613</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Demonstration</Title>
<Details>A picture is worth a thousand words. A demonstration is worth a thousand pictures. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>614</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Development Questions</Title>
<Details>How am I making our learning environment supportive? How am I making our learning environment purposeful? How am I making our learning environment interactive? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>615</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Dismissal</Title>
<Details>Before being dismissed any trash, papers, or items on the floor must to be picked up. &apos;We leave the room in the same way we like to find it.&apos; </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>616</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Draw Me The Answer</Title>
<Details>Students have mini whiteboards. A) Show me what StudyTopic looks like. B) Draw the 2 most important StudyTopic ideas. C) What does StudyTopic look like upside down? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>617</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Encourage Questions</Title>
<Details>In some cultures students do not question teachers. Find opportunities for all students to practice (clarification, repetition and simplification) StudyTopic questions: &apos;Was this what you meant? Please could you repeat the question? Can you explain that in a simpler way?&apos; </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>618</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Explain Why</Title>
<Details>Be positive and don&apos;t offer empty praise. Tell students why their performance was &apos;good&apos;. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>619</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Grading</Title>
<Details>Students call out their self-graded marks and they are recorded directly into the class mark book. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>620</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Handing In</Title>
<Details>For quicker paper collection have students pass papers across the rows and then down the line. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>621</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Interesting Roll Call</Title>
<Details>Instead of saying &apos;Here&apos; students give their answer to the question: What is your favorite StudyTopic word? At end of the register question students. &apos;Billy, what was Franks favorite StudyTopic word?&apos; </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>622</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Learning Objective Achieved</Title>
<Details>How will students know that they have achieved the learning objective.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>623</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Learning Talk</Title>
<Details>What percentage of the lesson is Teacher Talk? What percentage of the lesson is Student Talk? How can I best maximize student learning? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>624</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Leaving Open Books</Title>
<Details>As you leave I want you to put your book open on the work that you have done today. (This will make marking quicker as there will be no need to flick through pages). </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>625</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Mini Assessment</Title>
<Details>At what point can I use a mini assessment to give learners a sense of progress in StudyTopic? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>626</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Names Written</Title>
<Details>Remind all students to check they have their name on their StudyTopic work before they hand it in. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>627</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Narrow Down Answers</Title>
<Details>Narrow down learners&apos; answers: Can you be more specific in your StudyTopic answer? Can you give more details? How is that connected to the StudyTopic question? How does that bear on the issue? How does your answer address the complexities in the question? How are you taking into account the problems in the question? Is that dealing with the most significant StudyTopic factor(s)? What would this problem look like from a conservative standpoint? What would this look like from the point of view of .....?  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>628</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Next Lesson</Title>
<Details>How will I identify the StudyTopic concepts and skills that learners need to work on next lesson? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>629</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Nonverbal Feedback</Title>
<Details>Communicate with students using non-verbal feedback, it is quick and conveys the message more effectively: a Smile, a Gesture, a Motion. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>630</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Note</Title>
<Details>Make a note of what has been completed with students ald use that as the starting point for the next lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>631</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Numbered Work</Title>
<Details>Students write their mark book number in the top right hand side of their work. At the end of the class students hand their work in mark book order. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>632</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Open Question</Title>
<Details>How am I going about making this lesson accessible to everyone? What techniques can I use to make the lesson more accessible? How can I use open questions to increase accessibility? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>633</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Participation</Title>
<Details>What might be the reasons be that students don&apos;t engage with the activities in this lesson? What would I need to do to get everyone participating? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>634</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Personalize: Nicknames</Title>
<Details>Personalize my teaching style by asking pupils to think of StudyTopic nicknames and then using them during the lesson. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>635</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Review Vocabulary</Title>
<Details>During the lesson we will review the vocabulary from the previous lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>636</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Show Me The Answer!</Title>
<Details>Using mini-whiteboards, true/false cards, hand signals, different colored cards, etc. Periodically check students&apos; understanding with 3 quick questions. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>637</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Speak UP</Title>
<Details>I have a bad ear infection. Please speak up. What was that? Do please speak louder! </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>638</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Speedy Entry</Title>
<Details>The last student to enter the classroom will do a review of StudyTopic at the end. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>639</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Student Understanding</Title>
<Details>Ask questions that demonstrates understanding: What things can you think of that are similar to StudyTopic? In what places might you find StudyTopic? Can you see any dangers to StudyTopic? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>640</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Students To Watch</Title>
<Details>Keep an eye on the following students; StudentNames. These students respond well to praise and positive encouragement. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>641</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Success</Title>
<Details>Focus on celebrating success, individually and as a group. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>642</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Timer</Title>
<Details>Put a count down timer onto the board to show students exactly how long there is left to complete the task. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>643</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Transitions</Title>
<Details>How will the transitions happen between the different parts of the lesson? How can I make the transitions happen smoothly? </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>644</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Win-Win</Title>
<Details>What will help to make this StudyTopic lesson a win-win experience for everyone (students, teaching assistants and teacher) in the class?</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>645</ID>
<Section>Reminder</Section>
<Title>Zero Words</Title>
<Details>Improve communication by using zero words. Point, model and act out the StudyTopic tasks and activities. Use facial expressions and body language.  </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>646</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Class Information</Title>
<Details>The details for the class, areas the class are focussing on and points to bear in mind are: </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>647</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Confidential</Title>
<Details>For confidentiality the specific name(s) of those students with educational needs, health conditions and physical challenges are not included. Specific names and full alass lists of medical and learning needs can be accessed from the school&apos;s electronic  database or the school records department.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>648</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Ability Challenged: None</Title>
<Details>In the class there are no students that are ability challenged.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>649</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Ability Challenged: Student</Title>
<Details>There is 1 student who is ability challenged. Consideration needs to be given to their ability to move around the classroom and safely participate in physical activities.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>650</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Ability Challenged: Students</Title>
<Details>There are 2 students who are ability challenged. Consideration needs to be given to their ability to move around the classroom and safely participate in physical activities.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>651</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Ability: Mixed</Title>
<Details>The class is a mixed ability group.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>652</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Ability: Sets</Title>
<Details>This is class 1 of 4 sets, with the highest ability students placed into set 1 and the lowest ability students in set 4.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>653</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Attainment Range: A+ to C</Title>
<Details>The range of attainment of students in the class goes from A+ to C.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>654</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Attainment Range: A+ to F</Title>
<Details>The range of attainment of students in the class goes from A+ to F.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>655</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Attainment Range: C to G</Title>
<Details>The range of attainment of students in the class goes from C to G.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>656</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Attendance/ Absentees</Title>
<Details>There are several students that have missed several weeks of work. These students may need extra attention in getting started and providing them with a basic understanding of StudyTopic so that they can understand the task(s).</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>657</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>English As An Additional Language</Title>
<Details>There are several students for whom English is an additional language (EAL). To address this need it important to take care to speak clearly, demonstrate what is required and check that those students understand what is required of them. The classroom seating plan is design so that EAL students are seated cloqe to a native speaker to help in understanding tasks.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>658</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Gifted And Talented: Two Students</Title>
<Details>There is 1 gifted and talented student in the class. The lesson will stretah and challenge this student by providing differentiated learning objectives. Overall this will result in learning outcomes that are fulfill the needs of the Gifted and Talented student.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>659</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Gifted And Talented: Two Students</Title>
<Details>There are 2 gifted and talented students in the class. The lesson will stretch and challenge these students by providing differentiated learning objectives. Overall this will result in learning outcomes that are fulfill the needs of the Gifted and Talented students.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>660</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Individual Educational Plan</Title>
<Details>In the class there are no students that have an individual educational plan.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>661</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Learning Challenge: ADHD</Title>
<Details>There is 1 student(s) that has Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (also know as ADD - Attention Deficit Disorder ) and they have poor concentration, hyperactivity, and learning difficulties.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>662</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Learning Challenge: Asperger&apos;s</Title>
<Details>There is 1 student(s) that finds social interaction awkward. They are very particular with wording and have a narrow set of interest. Frame their learning within a context of familiar ideas.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>663</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Learning Challenge: Autism</Title>
<Details>There is 1 student(s) that has Autism and they have great difficulty in communicating and forming relationships with other people and in using language and abstract concepts.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>664</ID>
<Section>Class Informatimn</Section>
<Title>Learning Challenge: Dyslexia</Title>
<Details>There is 1 student(s) who has dyslexia and finds it difficult to interpret words, letters and symbols. Ensure that writing on the board is large and clear. Print handouts on yellow paper. Avoid unnecessary noise to allow the student(s) to focus. Provide a framework to assist in structuring of essays and written work. Make learning tactile to allow the student to differentiate. Encourage the use of a dictionary to check spelling(s). Avoid dyslexic students being overwhelmed with complexity by breaking down the task(s) into a series of manageable chunks.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>665</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Learning Challenge: Dyspraxia</Title>
<Details>There is 1 student(s) who has dyspraxia and has difficulty with activities requiring coordination and movement. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>666</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Previous Learning: Continuation</Title>
<Details>This StudyTopic lesson will be a continuation of previous lessons where students have been working on StudyTopic.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>667</ID>
<Section>Class Informatimn</Section>
<Title>Previous Learning: None</Title>
<Details>This is the first time that students will have encountered StudyTopic. A few students have a limited understanding of StudyTopic</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>668</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Previous Learning: Started</Title>
<Details>Students have been working on this topic during the previous lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>669</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Raising Boys&apos; Achievement</Title>
<Details>The average attainment of boys is lower than that of girls. Students sat boy/girl (where possible) to maximize performance. Use paired tasks with engaging, active and kinesthetic activities. Maximize oppmrtunities to explore understanding with discussion.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>670</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Raising Girls&apos; Achievement</Title>
<Details>The average attainment of girls is lover than that of boys. Students are sat boy/girl (where possible) to maximize student learning.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>671</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Seating Plan</Title>
<Details>There is a seating plan and students know where they are sat. The seating plan can be found in the class folder on the teacher&apos;s desk.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>672</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Seating: Ability Groups</Title>
<Details>The students are sat in mixed ability groups.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>673</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Seating: Boy/ Girl</Title>
<Details>Students are sat Boy/ Girl/ Boy/ Girl.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>674</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Seating: Chosen</Title>
<Details>Students choose their own seating and grouping. This gives students a sense mf individuality and autonomy within the classroom.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>675</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Seating: Groups</Title>
<Details>Students will sit according to the groups that they will be working in.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>676</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Seating: Varies</Title>
<Details>The seating of students varies according the task that is being carried out.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>677</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>SEN Pupil: One Student</Title>
<Details>There is 1 SEN pupil. Their needs are </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>678</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>SEN Pupils: Two Students</Title>
<Details>There are 2 SEN pupils. Their needs are </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>679</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Special Needs: None</Title>
<Details>In the class there are no Special Education Needs students.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>680</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Student Numbers</Title>
<Details>There are 30 students in the class, 15 boys and 15 girls.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>681</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Support Qtaff: One</Title>
<Details>Thepe is 1 teaching assistant that assists with the class. The teaching assistant is present for the majority of the classes and they have a good relationship with the students. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>682</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Support Staff: Two</Title>
<Details>There are 2 teaching assistants that support with the class. The teaching assistant is present for the majority of the classes and they have a good relationship with the students. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>683</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Teaching Assistant Focus</Title>
<Details>There is a teaching assistant assigned to this class. The focus of the teaching assistant is on 3 of the lower attaining pupils by attainment grade.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>684</ID>
<Section>Class Information</Section>
<Title>Teaching Assistants Focus</Title>
<Details>There are 2 teaching assistants assigned to this class. The focus of the teaching assistants are on 4 of the lower attaining pupils.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>685</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Lesson Safety</Title>
<Details>In order to maximize student, teacher and observer safety the precautions that must be taken into account for this StudyTopic lesson are: </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>686</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Identify As Needed</Title>
<Details>To create a safe and productive classroom during this StudyTopic lesson due care and attention must be given towards health and safety. Issues must be identified as and when they transpire and appropriate action taken to ensure the safety and wellbeing of everyone within the classroom. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>687</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Blade</Title>
<Details>You are going to be working with a blade. You must keep your fingers away from the blade. Before you do anything look at what is going on around you. You are responsible for keeping yourself safe and watching out for the safety of everyone else. Watch my demonstration carefully to ensure that you and your fingers are safe.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>688</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Blow Back </Title>
<Details>When you heat the test tube the air inside will expand. What happens when you stop heating? If the liquid gets pulled into the tube then it will shatter the glass. It is essential that you have your safety glasses on at all times. Watch the demonstration carefully before you carry out this experiment. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>689</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Checklist</Title>
<Details>1. Elimination- Can I cease the activity with potential for harm? (answer will generally be no but it must be seriously considered, what is the need?) 2. Substitution- Can I replace substances or processes with something that is safer? 3. Engineering controls- Can you do something physical to make an activity safer (i.e. guarding a dangerous machine/ providing suitable edge protection to prevent falls from height (there is no safe distance to fall from height)). 4. Administrative controls- Safe systems of work/methods of working/ training /instruction/ authorization. 5. Personal Protective Equipment- after all previous measures have been considered the final level of control is PPE which must be suitable for the task. Has there been training? What are the limitations?</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>690</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Computer Equipment</Title>
<Details>You will be working on the computer for an extended length of time. It&apos;s important for you to think about your posture. You should be upright and not slouched. Check that your chair is at a comfortable height so that you can work on the keyboard without straining. Your screen should be at an angle so that you can easily see it.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>691</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Departmental Risk Assessment</Title>
<Details>The departmental risk assessments contains details of the risks, dangers and precautions for this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>692</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Evaluate</Title>
<Details>Step 1 Identify the hazards: Step 2 Decide who might be harmed and how: Step 3 Evaluate the risks and decide on precautions: Step 4 Record your findings and implement them: Step 5 Review your assessment and update if necessary:</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>693</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Eye Protection</Title>
<Details>Eye protection must be worn throughout the designated sections of the lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>694</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Food</Title>
<Details>You will be working with and then consuming food. Food safety rules must be followed.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>695</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Fragile Materials</Title>
<Details>You are going to be working with a fragile material. There is a danger of it cracking or breaking. You must take care.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>696</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Fume Cupboard</Title>
<Details>Sections of this lesson involve the use of volatile chemicals and synthesis of volatile products. To minimize the risk of inhalation those sections of the experiment must take place in a fume cupboard.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>697</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Heating</Title>
<Details>Due to the risk of material catching alight, long hair must be tied back. Ties, cardigans and scarves are not permitted to hang freely.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>698</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Height</Title>
<Details>You will be working at a height. You must always have two feet on a solid surface. Use both of your hands when climbing up or climbing down off a surface.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>699</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Hot Materials</Title>
<Details>You will be handling hot materials, to minimize the risk of burns you must use safety gloves for handling hot materials and equipment.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>700</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Chemicals: Irritant</Title>
<Details>The materials that we will be working with in this lesson are irritants. You must avoid the materials coming into contact with your skin. If you do come into contact you must tell a member of staff straight away.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>701</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Microbiology</Title>
<Details>In order to reduce the risk of cross-contamination sterile technique and sterile conditions must be maintained throughout this experiment.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>702</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>No Specific Issues</Title>
<Details>There are no specific health and safety issues that need to be considered within this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>703</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Off-Site Activity</Title>
<Details>In order to make sure that you are safe I need to know where you are at all times. You must be in sight of a member of staff at all times.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>704</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Physical Activity</Title>
<Details>Due to the risk of choking there is to be no chewing gum, no eating and no drinking during the class.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>705</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Chemicals: Poisonous</Title>
<Details>Due to the risk of ingesting poisonous chemicals there is to be no chewing gum, no eating and no drinking during the class. Gloves must be worn during the handling of the reactants and products.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>706</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Projectile Danger</Title>
<Details>There is a risk of projectiles leaving the demonstration. A tall safety screen must be in place between you and the demonstration. Everyone must be 2 meters away from the screen and everyone must wear safety glasses.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>707</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Scissors</Title>
<Details>You will be working with scissors. If you are left handed then take a left handed pair which have a different colored haldle. When you come and collect your scissors they must be closed. Carry your scissors to your desk holding them by the main part of the scissors. You must only start using the scissors once you have got all of your equipment.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>708</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Sharp Objects</Title>
<Details>In order to ensure that we have got all of the sharp equipment we are using we are going to count out and then in all sharp objects we are using.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>709</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Strenuous Physical Activity</Title>
<Details>The lesson involves a period of strenuous physical activity. To avoid the risk of asthmatic attack or other medical condition you must say if there is any medical reason you can&apos;t take part in this activity.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>710</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Test Tube Heating</Title>
<Details>The tube must be no more than one fifth full and be pointing away from your own and other peoples faces. You must heat the tube gradually, at a 45 angle while gently swirling your tube. No sitting is permitted during this part of the experiment.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>711</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Weights</Title>
<Details>You will be carrying heavy weights. Ensure that you lift using your legs and not your back.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>712</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Chemicals: Toxic</Title>
<Details>We will be working with toxic materials. Lab coat and eye protection must be worn at all times. It is essential that gloves are worn thoughout the lesson. All materials must be disposed of in the toxic waste bin.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>713</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Chemicals: Caustic</Title>
<Details>We will be working with caustic materials. Lab coat and eye protection must be worn at all times. It is essential that gloves are worn thoughout the lesson. All materials must be disposed of in the toxic waste bin.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>714</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Chemicals: Carcinogenic</Title>
<Details>We will be working with carcinogenic materials. Lab coat and eye protection must be worn at all times. It is essential that gloves are worn thoughout the lesson. All materials must be disposed of in the toxic waste bin.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>715</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Radioactive Material</Title>
<Details>We will be working with radioactive material. It is essential that the material is handled using the directions given.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>716</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Chemicals: Explosive</Title>
<Details>We will be working with explosive chemicals. Lab coat and eye protection must be worn at all times. It is essential that gloves are worn thoughout the lesson. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>717</ID>
<Section>Safety</Section>
<Title>Bio Hazard</Title>
<Details>We will be working with carcinogenic materials. Lab coat and eye protection must be worn at all times. It is essential that gloves are worn thoughout the lesson. All materials must be disposed of in the bio-hazard waste bin.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>718</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Additional Information</Title>
<Details>Additional information and notes about the lesson: </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>719</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Maximizing Learning</Title>
<Details>During this lesson we will be working on tackling the misconceptions that many students have about StudyTopic. There will be an opportunity for independent practice through writing and speaking activities. The lesson will be differentiated through both tasks and seating. A paired teaching activity will be used to accelerate student progress. Assessment of learning will take place thoughout the lesson and the activities will be modified according to student feedback. At the end of the lesson there will be an assessment to provide students with feedback of their attainment and achievements.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>720</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Additional Key Questions</Title>
<Details>Additional questions that have not been included within the lesson sections but may be used as and when are necessary are: </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>721</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Assessment For Learning</Title>
<Details>Assessment for learning will take place using a quizzes and a mini test carried out during the lesson. Additional strategies that will be used as and when necessary are; questions and answers, work sheets, listening, self assessment e.g. traffic lighting, peer assessment, sharing learning objectives, feedback for learning, sharing levels and observation.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>722</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Assessment Of Learning</Title>
<Details>Assessment of learning will take place throughout the lesson, using traffic light cards, fan cards, thumbs up/ down, stand up/ sit down. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>723</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Background Knowledge</Title>
<Details>What students already know about StudyTopic is</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>724</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Differentiation: Learning Outcome</Title>
<Details>Students will each have differentiated learning outcomes by choosing their own learning objective; Must, Should and Could. The most able students will be carrying out the Could objective, intermediate students will complete the Should objective and all students will complete the &apos;Must&apos; objective. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>725</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Differentiation: Seating</Title>
<Details>Differentiation will be taking place by seating lower attaining students with higher attaining students. Peer teaching will enable paired students to make greater progress. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>726</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Differentiation: Task</Title>
<Details>The StudyTopic lesson will use a series of short tasks to aid students with a shorter concentration span. The lesson will also utilize Must, Should and Could task objectives, with the most able students carrying out the Could objective.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>727</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Evaluation</Title>
<Details>Following the lesson I will carry out an evaluation of student achievement: What evidence is there that students have achieved each of the learning objectives? What are the key moments of achievement during the lesson? What were the key difficulties during the lesson? How appropriate were the activities in meeting the varied learning needs of the students? How could the assessment for learning be improved in monitoring the progress and capturing the achievement of all students? If I was to do this lesson again what would I do differently? What must I do to improve the learning experience for this class during our next lesson?</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>728</ID>
<Section>Additional Informatimn</Section>
<Title>Independent Practice: Speaking</Title>
<Details>There will be an opportunity for independent practice because students will be speaking.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>729</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>Independent Practice: Writing</Title>
<Details>There will be an opportunity for independent practice because students will be writing.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>730</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>No Additional Information</Title>
<Details>There is no additional lesson information for this StudyTopic lesson.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>731</ID>
<Section>Additional Informatimn</Section>
<Title>PDP Action Point</Title>
<Details>Linking to the Personal Development Plan (PDP) the action point that will be addressed during this StudyTopic lesson is </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>732</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>PIP Action Point</Title>
<Details>Linking to the Performance Improvement Plan (PIP) the action point that will be addressed during this StudyTopic lesson is </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>733</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>SDP Attainment</Title>
<Details>Linking to the Qchool Development Plan (SDP) this lesson will be focused on raising the attainment of all students. By the end of the lesson all students will have their attainment level and a target level. Students will identify their own target(s) to raise their attainment.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>734</ID>
<Section>Additional Information</Section>
<Title>StudyTopic Misconception</Title>
<Details>Some of the StudyTopic misconceptions that students have are: </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>735</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Analyzing</Title>
<Details>Separating or breaking a whole into parts to discover their nature, functional and relationships. I studied it piece by piece. I sorted things out.</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>736</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Applying Standards</Title>
<Details>Judging according to established personal, professional, or social rules or criteria. I judged it according to... </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>737</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Discriminating</Title>
<Details>Recognizine differences and similarities among things or situations and distinguishing carefully as to category or rank. I rank ordered the various… I grouped things together </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>738</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Information Seeking</Title>
<Details>Searching for evidence, facts, or knowledge by identifying relevant sources and gathering objective, subjective, historical, and current data from those sources. I knew I needed to lookup/study… I kept searching for data. </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>739</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Logical Reasoning</Title>
<Details>Drawing inferences or conclusions that are supported in or justified by evidence. I deduced from the information that… My rationale for the conclusion was…</Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>740</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Predicting</Title>
<Details>Envisioning a plan and its consequences. I envisioned the outcome would be… I was prepared for... </Details>
</vqplan>
<vqplan>
<ID>741</ID>
<Section>Critical Thinking</Section>
<Title>Transforming Knowledge</Title>
<Details>Changing or converting the condition, nature, form, or function of concepts among contexts. I improved on the basics by… I wondered if that would fit the situation of …</Details>
</vqplan>
</dataroot>
